<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>putz.space</title><link href="https://putz.space/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://putz.space/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://putz.space/</id><updated>2019-07-23T17:06:37-05:00</updated><entry><title>Happy birthday to me!</title><link href="https://putz.space/blog/happy-bday-to-me/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-23T17:06:37-05:00</published><updated>2019-07-23T17:06:37-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-07-23:/blog/happy-bday-to-me/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I decided to do an open reflection for my 25th birthday. It's definitely weird being an adult, but I'm hoping to get back into music and find time for exciting new stuff. Mostly I just wanted to let people who haven't heard from me in a while know how things are going. Hope you're doing well!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="derpy birthday cake" src="https://putz.space/blog/covers/bday-cake.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://clipartmag.com/images/40th-birthday-clipart-25.png"&gt;img src&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Welp, I'm an adult now&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well shit, it's officially my birthday. I had a good time celebrating with family and friends over the weekend instead of the day of, because work and stuff, but I wanted to take some time to write to folks on such a monumentous birthday as my 25th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing that's striking though is how mundane today, my actual birthday, feels. Of course, the older you get the more birthdays you've had and the less special they feel. But it's an odd feeling the older I get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Staying in touch is hardy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I haven't done a great job of staying in touch, it's not because I don't want to. As I'm sure you understand, life can take you in different directions than the people you care about because shit just gets busy. Working full time doesn't leave you with a whole lot of room for much else! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I recently moved to a more central location &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; inside the city I live in, so maybe some of that will change. If you're near by you can come visit! Feel free to &lt;a href="mailto:inbox@putz.space"&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;. I'll be trying to do the same in the coming months (hopefully).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;I haven't forgotten about music!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides friends, it's been interesting to see how the shift into adulthood has impacted my hobbies as well. I used to be much more active with my music. My identity was heavily wrapped up in being Groove Masta Putz. It still is of course (admittedly less so though), but lately I've barely had time to even &lt;em&gt;listen&lt;/em&gt; to music, let alone make it. So I've been struggling to put anything out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However I still find inspiration here and there for music ideas, so I intend to get back to it once I'm 100% moved into my new place and have the studio set up. I even have a room to dedicate as an actual studio now, so that should help. I'm hoping to upgrade my equipment too now that I'm slightly more financially stable lol. If you're really out of the loop you can see my latest music on the &lt;a href="https://putz.space/music/"&gt;music section&lt;/a&gt; by the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Where to go from here?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm still exploring how I want to use this website. Finding time to be creative has been challenging. I still have design issues to fix and features to add, but I suppose I'll get to it eventually. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creative writing would be fun, writing more tutorials or who knows what. I've been having intrusive thoughts of story telling here and there, so maybe I'll actually act on it. Surprisingly, some blog posts have been relevant in actual conversations I've had so that's pretty cool too! Either way, expect more as I get settled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a lot I'd like to say to the folks I haven't seen in a while, but mostly I hope you're all doing well. I genuinely miss quite a few people, but you're all out there doin' it big so I'm happy for you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally I'm at a fairly good spot in my life right now, even though for many I know times are tough. Hopefully you're doing well, because in spite of how crazy the world is right now I'm actually looking forward to what the future holds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until Next Time,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Putz&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>Ways to replace Facebook</title><link href="https://putz.space/blog/ways-to-replace-facebook/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-06-26T19:58:50-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-26T19:58:50-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-06-26:/blog/ways-to-replace-facebook/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A friend on my feed recently shared a story about a day in the life of a Facebook moderator, which unsurprisingly isn't a great time. After reading it they were asking themself if they could genuinely leave Facebook. That inspired me to ask the question on my feed "What keeps you on Facebook?", hoping that I could write about my experience leaving and what I did to replace the things that kept me there. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Facebook logo" src="https://putz.space/blog/covers/ways-to-replace-facebook.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href="https://fanpagecash.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/leaving-facebook.png"&gt;https://fanpagecash.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/leaving-facebook.png&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend on my feed recently shared &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/19/18681845/facebook-moderator-interviews-video-trauma-ptsd-cognizant-tampa" target="_blank"&gt;a story about a day in the life of a Facebook moderator&lt;/a&gt;, which unsurprisingly isn't a great time. After reading it they were asking themself if they could genuinely leave Facebook. That inspired me to ask the question on my feed "What keeps you on Facebook?", hoping that I could write about my experience leaving and what I did to replace the things that kept me there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I may be back for now, I think I found some solutions that could help people for a few problems I was having when I finally decided to leave it. Hopefully this can serve as inspiration to you in your pursuit to finally hop off of Facebook, but if not you can at least implement one or two of these things and slowly add more over time so that when you feel confident enough to hit the permanent delete button, you'll be ready. Most of this can peacefully co-exist with Facebook too honestly anyway, so maybe it'll be useful even if you never leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could go on a long philosophical rant about why you should leave, from the privacy invasions characteristic of a dystopian novel to the huge amounts of mental energy it can suck away from you, but I'm sure if you're reading this you already have your own reasons for being interested in leaving or entertaining the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sad reality is that in some ways Facebook may be the best place for certain stuff depending on what your goals are or what you're looking for. However, you'd be surprised just how easy it really is to get by without Facebook. Admittedly, I'm back on it though, but &lt;a href="https://putz.space/blog/returning-to-facebook/"&gt;I wrote about why at length already&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've ordered this list based on what I've found most important personally. It reflects my own needs, so for some of the missing pieces you may have to do your own digging still. I did conduct a Facebook poll to try and see what people use theirs for to get an idea of what people might want to read about. So while I could go on about all of Facebook's features, I've decided to stick to my own experience and what people cared to hear about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it's a long one...
&lt;div id="toc"&gt;
&lt;p id="toc-header"&gt;Contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#feed"&gt;News feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#socialmedia"&gt;Social media&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#music"&gt;Music &amp;amp; sharing projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#photos"&gt;Photos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#messaging"&gt;Messaging and friends list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#events"&gt;Events&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#chronicle"&gt;Chronicle of life events&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="feed"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;News feed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly a pretty big one in my limited survey. Facebook's algorithm makes following news sources highly unpredictable which is super annoying if you want the latest updates from sources you trust. So instead of dealing with that bullshit, you can use &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS" target="_blank"&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt;. Click the link if you want the scoop on it, but I'm just focusing on how to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing you need to find is an RSS reader. Think of it as a personal electronic mailbox that's on your digital doorfront. So what you need are addresses that stuff your mail box with chronologically sorted, no-bullshit news straight from your favorite publications as they push them out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding an RSS feed on a website can sometimes be complicated. In fact, it's not garaunteed you'll even find one, but usually it's accompanied by this cute logo: &lt;a href="http://putz.space/feeds/all.rss.xml"&gt;&lt;img src="https://putz.space/images/articles/rss.png" alt="RSS" width="16px" height="16px" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is that some RSS readers will just find the feed if you enter in the website's address though, so you might not even have to think about it too hard depending on what you go with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use RSS to follow podcasts, YouTube channels, blogs, you name it. In fact, you can use it to follow my own blog! I try to make it simple, so you can &lt;a href="http://putz.space/feeds/all.atom.xml" target="_blank"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt; or the logo above to copy the address to add me. It's just that sometimes other websites don't advertise this functionality for whatever reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have trouble finding an RSS feed, try googling it. A simple "[website] rss feed" will suffice usually, but in one case I was trying to follow the local news and I was getting stumped on finding any RSS functionality. However, I googled the name of the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Content_management_system" target="_blank"&gt;CMS (Content Management System)&lt;/a&gt; that I found at the bottom of the page and added "rss" to the search and it took me to the documentation for the software they use. Turns out, all I had to do was add &amp;amp;f=rss at the end of the URL after using their website's search function and it worked! Usually it's easier than that though. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Practice on my own blog if you'd like by adding it into a feed reader of your choice. Some web browsers even have readers of their own built in. There's a variety of readers to choose from, some only working locally on the computer they're installed on and others being online subscription services you can use that will be stored in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If RSS is too complicated for your tastes, there are other ways to get your news from Google to Apple to Reddit, but this puts more control over who you get to see in your own hands without algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refer to these links for more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison_of_feed_aggregators#Operating_system_support" target="_blank"&gt;Wikipedia - List of Feed Aggregators by OS they're available on&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://fossbytes.com/best-rss-reader-apps/" target="_blank"&gt;Fossbytes - Best RSS reader apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lifewire.com/top-free-online-rss-readers-3486649" target="_blank"&gt;Lifewire - Best online RSS readers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="socialmedia"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Social media&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping up with friends and family, besides following the news, was hands down the biggest reason people are still on Facebook. Which makes sense, because that's the reason I'm back. Honestly, I haven't really found an alternative that I would claim allows you to stay in touch with friends as well as I'd like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, there are alternatives like Reddit, Snapchat and Instagram, but Instagram is owned by Facebook anyway so it's like a different room of the same house. I do find it less addictive though so maybe that or Snapchat could be a way to stay in touch if you find Facebook problematic for whatever reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did dive into an alternative up-and-coming social media platform called &lt;a href="https://fediverse.party/en/fediverse/" target="_blank"&gt;"The Fediverse"&lt;/a&gt;. The technology has some great potential to reshape the social media landscape in the face of increasing concerns over Facebook's monopoly of our online social lives. The way it works is it lets a bunch of different platforms communicate with each other through a standarized protocol. It'd be like if Facebook and Twitter would let you subscribe to users from either platform, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The low barrier to entry gives communities an easy way to create their own online space so that they can have more control over them without corporate influence. It's devoid of any advertisements, bullshit feed algorithms that prey on your pscyhe, and has a somewhat healthier community (parts of it anyhow) that actually wants to invite people to be themselves without all the hate you find elsewhere. It's not perfect, but it's neat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally use &lt;a href="http://joinmastodon.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; with the handle &lt;a href="https://mastodon.technology/@nergalur" target="_blank"&gt;@nurgalur@mastodon.technology&lt;/a&gt; (at the time of writing anyway, see the about/contact page for the latest if this link is broken), but if you dig around there are other ways to set up your own account. Pretty much only lefty nerds interested in tech and queer people of color are on there right now, so it might be a niche only interesting to myself and a select few Facebook friends for the time being. The memes are pretty funny too, but it takes a while to get the in-jokes. Anyway, probably not for everyone, but that's been my journey into the realm of alternative social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="music"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Music &amp;amp; sharing projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly I wasn't the only one who wanted to find a way to share my music, and by extension personal projects, with friends. It's one of the reasons I've returned to Facebook before. I would previously share SoundCloud links on my feed for friends to keep up with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But honestly, SoundCloud is pretty damn awful. At least sound quality wise, although the interface is decent enough. Listening to any of the higher frequencies in a song though makes it apparent that SoundCloud is clearly not making enough money or something because that shit is compressed as hell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I actually ended up making this website with my own &lt;a href="https://putz.space/music/" target="_blank"&gt;music&lt;/a&gt; section to fix that problem. By using GitHub pages I have free hosting for &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Static_web_page" target="_blank"&gt;static web pages&lt;/a&gt;, all I had to buy was the domain name for the website (~$3-11/yr depending) and use &lt;a href="https://blog.getpelican.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; to generate the website with. There's technically a limit to how much you can upload, but 1GB is a lot of space for a blog before you start having problems with storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still link to other places you can find my music like Bandcamp and SoundCloud depending on where I've uploaded it to, but this way people can at least come to me to find the best quality version of my work, even if they prefer to listen to it elsewhere. You can also share all your music with something like &lt;a href="http://distrokid.com" target="_blank"&gt;DistroKid&lt;/a&gt; which will distribute it for like $20/yr, whether or not you have a website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the actual "publicity" side of things, that's beyond the scope of this article and I'm not really the one you should consult on "getting big", but by having my own web page people will at least always know where they can find me, whether I'm on Facebook or not. I also intend to use this space for any other projects I get involved in, but music has been my biggest so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="photos"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Photos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social media has created a convenient way for people to keep track of all of their photos, and Facebook is quite useful. However, "you never really know what you've got until it's gone" as the saying goes, and it's particularly true when the Internet is down and you can't access your shit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's why I use an external hard drive to back up all my important photos. Really there's no reason not to use an online service like what's offered by Google, Apple, Facebook or Instagram as well as having your photos backed up locally, but I personally don't find myself sharing my photos that often anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set up my own local over-the-network backup solution that automatically transfers my photos from my phone to my computer, which I'd like to write about more at some point in the future (definitely beyond the scope of this article), but even just following the routine of backing up any photos from your phone/camera to a hard drive every month is a simple way to make sure you don't lose everything if your phone dies. It's also nice for any photos you wouldn't want to lose in a security leak or by having your account suspended by surprise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S: If you have photos on Facebook you want to download there's a way to actually download your entire photo collection, just search "download facebook photo backup".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as sharing photos though, I haven't really looked around a whole lot because honestly it doesn't matter as much to me and I feel weird about putting my photos online a lot of times anyway. But if it does matter to you, you'll have to do your own digging and let me know what you find because as far as I'm aware, Instagram, Snapchat and Facebook are the best in town for that one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="messaging"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Messaging and friends list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one was pretty important to me, but super easy to replace. You can literally think of anything you use that isn't Facebook and you're already there. I use Signal, Telegram, SMS, Email, Instagram (although technically also owned by Facebook), Whatsapp (same boat as Instagram), sometimes I check my Snapchat, but honestly you probably don't need my help to find a technical solution here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use Facebook to get all of your friends contact info and put it into whatever you use to save your contacts. If you have a phone you probably already have some cloud-based way of doing this. If you want to hop off the cloud though, you can opt to save contacts locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my experience, I found it was very challenging to find the time in the day to keep up with nearly the same number of people though as I did through Facebook. The solution here is partly kinda beyond just finding the right technology unfortunately, which is a whole 'nother topic on its own. However, you might find that you just don't need to keep up with everyone you've met either, which is totally cool too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="events"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Events&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, it's not impossible to find events without Facebook! &lt;a href="http://meetup.com" target="_blank"&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; is very useful for finding events locally. Now actually going to them is another story. Something also true of Facebook when the real issue is finding the time to do anything ever lol, but it's a good alternative if you want to look around at what's going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For birthdays, some calendar apps even let you set friends' birthdays in your calendar from the contact info if you want to keep track of that. Could be another thing you add to your list of details to get from friends before you hop off Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other ways to find events include just looking at the local paper, or asking what your friends are up to and they'll probably let you know. Or if you go to a café or bar, sometimes they have a bulletin board. If there's a TV show you like or band they likely have a website you can visit with touring dates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granted, all of that is predicated on living in a city where people do things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="chronicle"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chronicle of life events&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People didn't mention this as a thing they particularly care about, however I notice some people use Facebook to post memories of way back from years ago. I honestly don't keep track of many of my personal milestones on Facebook, so it's not that useful to me for that. What I have found helpful for remembering those sorts of things is keeping a daily log which I wrote about extensively already, so if this is a reason you find yourself using Facebook, consider reading what &lt;a href="https://putz.space/blog/keep-it-together/"&gt;I wrote on that here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="conclusion"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully some of this has been helpful to you, or at the very least interesting. Some of these things are just good ideas, even if you don't plan on leaving, because they allow you to take back some of the control you've potentially given up over your digital life by letting Facebook take care of it. Even if you already deleted it, you can still do some of these things to replace the useful bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as I've said before you might not be able to replace everything to the same degree. Some of the things I didn't even touch on in this post such as groups, the marketplace, job postings, etc, either have more popular alternatives you can search for if you want or I just didn't use them enough to care. For example, I've gotten most job postings through Indeed or found used stuff on Craigslist. Some of the things you may have to decide to live without if you ever do finally decide to leave Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless, this has been a summary of my journey in finding ways to replace a few of the useful bits of Facebook through my numerous times leaving.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="tech"></category><category term="self-help"></category></entry><entry><title>How I keep it together</title><link href="https://putz.space/blog/keep-it-together/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-06-01T15:15:32-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-01T15:15:32-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-06-01:/blog/keep-it-together/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A while back in college I decided to start keeping a daily log and to-do list. That sparked a few routines that I started to use to keep my life together. I figured some people might find it helpful if I reflected on that journey and how I started adulting. So yeah, enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The titanic sinking in an infomercial" src="https://putz.space/blog/covers/keep-it-together.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided I want to openly reflect on how I organize my day to day because I think it could be helpful for people who are asking themselves how to do that. It's not a question I intentionally set out to answer when I started the routines that I use to keep track of my life and accomplish goals. However, these practices have lead me down a path that keep me focused and self aware so that I'm in tune with myself, my needs and where I'm going in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how did I get there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The daily log&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Zim wiki daily log" src="https://putz.space/images/diy/daily-log.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started keeping a daily log on December 17th, 2014. I originally started it because I was in college and I was bored at home over the winter. I was curious about learning the &lt;a href="http://python.org" target="_blank"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; programming language and I thought a good project would be to create my own note-taking software to help me in school. Then I quickly realized it would be a lot of work and decided instead to just find an open source project that someone already started (also written in Python) that would let me take notes more effectively than a bunch of scattered word docs all over My Documents like the rest of people in class. Fun fact, I still have those notes laying around too, even if I hardly reference them. At the time though, I found the software you see in the screenshot to be very useful for school too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting the habit of remembering to log my day was difficult, but not impossible the more I stuck with it. I was also inspired by a Life Pro-Tip I heard a while back on Reddit about keeping notes of all the happy moments in a year, putting them in a jar and opening the jar one New Years to remember the year. So instead of just the happy memories I decided to log the mundane and bad ones too. It's kinda fun to reflect back on and helps avoid the memory rot our brains are prone to when it comes to remembering certain details. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there I also had another idea...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;My to-do list&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Zim wiki to-do list" src="https://putz.space/images/diy/todo-list.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being on my own in college meant I had a new level of independence to be free with, but also live up to. In order to keep things straight I started to keep a to-do list, which I figured would go very well with the daily log. The nice thing about that combination is that you can set your goals and confirm with yourself whether you did them or not by simply reading the log. Over the years I've learned how to combine the two to recalibrate my life if I start to notice that I'm not getting done what I need to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this an unrealistic goal? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do I just need to define it better so it's more clear what to do? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the hell did I last get a hair cut again? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions like these and more are easier to answer if you have a running log of your life to double check if you're not even able to keep track of what you ate last for breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of these habits helped build into each other so I could maintain a routine that I wouldn't just simply stop doing one day from forgetting to do it. I also made sure that they were both simple enough to keep me doing them. The daily log is a mostly logistical thing for me, but I occassionally engage in more emotionally detailed reflections that I save in LibreOffice docs to go back to once and a while if I want, because that can be helpful for yourself too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main thing though, is organizing what you need to do in your life so that you don't forget to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, that's not accidentally capitalized while the others aren't. &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Getting_Things_Done" target="_blank"&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/a&gt; is an actual method some weird business lookin' boy from the year 2001 wrote for getting shit done. The software I use, &lt;a href="http://zim-wiki.org" target="_blank"&gt;Zim wiki&lt;/a&gt; includes an abridged explanation of how to integrate it into your workflow through the software, but anyway I'm gonna give you an even simpler run-down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, at some point I realized that my previous methods of keeping track of my to-do list were insufficient so I decided to investigate some more. The way I've adapted Getting Things Done is pretty simple. You don't even need to use the software I do to really implement this into your life, or any of these tips for that matter. You can work it into your life how makes the most sense to you. Creativity is the spice of life and all that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The flow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing you do is identify a task. Can it be done in less than 5 minutes? Then do it! Seriously, stuff like hanging up your clothes, putting a new toilet paper roll on the holder or loading and unloading a dishwasher are stuff that will vastly improve your quality of life without building up into a huge 30 minute mess down the line. So you'll be much better off for just doing them if you have the time. Sometimes we don't though, which is when you go to the next step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;INBOX and to-do list&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Zim wiki Inbox" src="https://putz.space/images/diy/todo-inbox.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write it down in my INBOX (as seen above) and if I can't think about it at the time then I just come back to it later. When I can take the time to process it (which I have a little reminder to do located at the top of the page so it shows up in Zim wiki's to-do list feature), I'll decide if it's something I genuinely want to put time into or discard. If it's a big project, I'll start to give it it's own space on a page of it's own under the Projects folder, otherwise you can just throw it on your everyday to-do or chores list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A chores list is something I look at frequently to remind myself what tasks I have to keep up with routinely (weekly, monthly, etc). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My to-do list is full of single, line item things that I need to take care of that might be related by subject matter but are independent stuff to do one time, probably at a certain date. Maybe I just have to pay a particular bill instead of one that is recurring for example or I should remember to call up a friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Projects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Zim wiki Project list: Automotive" src="https://putz.space/images/diy/todo-automotive.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Projects folder is where I take what is turning into a huge section of it's own list of related tasks all about one subject or on-going project in my life in the to-do list. My Automotive to-do list for example includes the entire maintenance schedule for my car, problems and repairs as they come up and anything related to my car, because that's how much is going on with it. That way I can make sure I'm up to date on the thing it needs taken care of routinely while keeping track of the small things that come up along the way like any rust spots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Someday&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last thing on the side panel you may see is the "SomeDay" folder. It's a place where I put anything I think of that isn't a task that's been formulated in concrete terms of when, what or how to do it. Maybe I would like to learn a thing, write an article or process an idea I'm having in a way more in-depth than my inbox. Or maybe something from the inbox is growing into a larger idea. I honestly haven't found myself using it that much, but it's a recommendation from the Getting Things Done method and I've been using it to just keep track of whims and dreams I have that I don't quite want to give up on yet but don't have any idea about what to do logistically for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you've made it this far you're clearly interested in trying to get your life together. I have found the above practices extremely fruitful when it comes to keeping it together for myself. Like I said, this turned out to be the product of what was more or less an accident and me wanting to nerd out on taking notes about myself because I was in college at the time and found those skills highly useful to transfer into my daily life. Unlike everyone else who went to college and "didn't learn anything useful", I found the mindset of being a self-directed studious individual has allowed me to optimize the way I spend my time so less of it is spent on shit that I've let get way out of control. Instead of letting my mind get scared of being bored and instantly type in facebook.com into my web browser, I try to direct my energies into this, certian times more successfully than others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see the memes of people who don't like to plan their life because they want it to be spontaneous or whatever, but actually having my shit all laid out in an easy to keep track of way has allowed me to have the ability to use my free time in the ways I truly want to, instead of dealing with unexpected consequences from letting one area of my life go to shit. It's not to say I don't run into ruts, roadblocks or stressful situations. These routines just allow me to deal with them more effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's certainly an element of luck and privilege as with anything in life as to why I've been able to keep my shit together. But I also found these skills useful and fundamental to my life as an adult so that I can be self-aware and on top of my shit. So take it for what you will, but I hope you may find my reflections useful. If you haven't, well my blog helps me process my life too so in the end it's all good anyway lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anything you can at least see where I got the inspiration from for my website's CSS style.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diy"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="self-help"></category><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>Groove Masta Putz - Morning Rise</title><link href="https://putz.space/music/demos/morning-rise/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-05-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-05-18:/music/demos/morning-rise/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Futuristic Society Tower" src="https://putz.space/blog/covers/morning-rise.jpg" id="article-image" /&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://ccsearch.creativecommons.org/photos/ddd846a6-3c34-4dc7-9e72-af0486a29df4"&gt;img source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio controls id="player"&gt;
    &lt;source id="song" src="https://putz.space/music/demos/Groove Masta Putz - Morning Rise.mp3" type="audio/mp3" /&gt;
    Your browser does not support the audio tag. See the arrow below for direct link.
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://putz.space/music/demos/Groove Masta Putz - Morning Rise.mp3"&gt;&lt;img alt="Direct link" src="https://putz.space/images/icons/download.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/groovemastaputz/groove-masta-putz-morning-rise"&gt;&lt;img alt="SoundCloud" src="https://putz.space/images/icons/soundcloud.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.newgrounds.com/audio/listen/863766"&gt;&lt;img alt="Newgrounds" src="https://putz.space/images/icons/newgrounds.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woke up this morning and decided go on a musical journey until I came up with this demo. Could expand later, but in the meantime let this take you on a journey through …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Futuristic Society Tower" src="https://putz.space/blog/covers/morning-rise.jpg" id="article-image" /&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://ccsearch.creativecommons.org/photos/ddd846a6-3c34-4dc7-9e72-af0486a29df4"&gt;img source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio controls id="player"&gt;
    &lt;source id="song" src="https://putz.space/music/demos/Groove Masta Putz - Morning Rise.mp3" type="audio/mp3" /&gt;
    Your browser does not support the audio tag. See the arrow below for direct link.
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://putz.space/music/demos/Groove Masta Putz - Morning Rise.mp3"&gt;&lt;img alt="Direct link" src="https://putz.space/images/icons/download.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/groovemastaputz/groove-masta-putz-morning-rise"&gt;&lt;img alt="SoundCloud" src="https://putz.space/images/icons/soundcloud.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.newgrounds.com/audio/listen/863766"&gt;&lt;img alt="Newgrounds" src="https://putz.space/images/icons/newgrounds.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woke up this morning and decided go on a musical journey until I came up with this demo. Could expand later, but in the meantime let this take you on a journey through... T H E F U T U R E.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Music licensed under the &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"&gt;Creative Commons 4.0 - Attribution license&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="music"></category><category term="demo"></category></entry><entry><title>How I learned DIY auto repair</title><link href="https://putz.space/blog/diy-car-repair/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-16T22:15:57-05:00</published><updated>2019-05-16T22:15:57-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-05-16:/blog/diy-car-repair/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ever since dealing with a crap car, it became clear I needed to learn more about cars. So here's how I did that! I focused on the process because there's already plenty of resources out there for specific repairs. I felt it would be helpful to look at how I prepared to do rust removal on my car as an example to share. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Derpy car" src="https://putz.space/blog/covers/diy-car-repair.png" width="400px" height="250px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fuckin' cars...&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let's make a long story short. I had an ok car that was high maintenance. It sucked. I decided that I was done dealing with the anxiety of what they're gonna find at the shop next. I was sick of wondering if the noises I hear from my car were normal or not. That lead me on my journey to finally learn what the hell is going on inside my car because until public transit is faster than 1.5hr each way to work, I'm gonna have to rely on one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;First steps&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing that you have to do before you can learn about any subject is how to speak the lingo. So I set out to learn the basics about car anatomy and terminology. What is each part called. What's a bearing? Why is it so expensive to repair a head gasket? What is that anyway? Stuff like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need somewhere to start you can always ask any mechanic buddies and see what they would say. Most will probably say they learned from an uncle or someone, so they can maybe help you out actually doing the repair if they're willing to take the time out of their day to do it (compensation helps). But online there are plenty of videos and I personally like reading so I found books to be very helpful as well. Something as simple as "Car Repair for Dummies" was actually quite foundational in explaining what everything is called and their place in your car's system. If you're a woman there are even books written by other women who speak to the particularities of car repair from a woman's perspective (like say, maybe dealing with assholes who don't take you seriously). Maybe there's community college classes. Find what speaks to you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some youtube channels I like, however you may have to search for stuff particular to your car because everyone has different vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/PaintballOO7"&gt;ChrisFix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/EricTheCarGuy"&gt;Eric the Car Guy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCT5dv3iwFuy041dbWPB6skg"&gt;Ratchets and Wrenches&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/1aauto"&gt;1A Auto Parts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don't have to go too deep though to find a lot useful information. If you really don't have the time to get a degree in cars then just take note of anything you have questions about while watching youtube videos and search any terms as you get stuck. This knowledge will accumulate over time even if the initial time investment may be a bit high at first. At the very least, you'll get an idea whether you need to take it in or if you can do it yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point is though, you need to figure out &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; you need to know and &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to learn it. Apply that to life!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Getting the tools&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step is to get any tools you'll need to actually apply that knowledge in the real world. The most essential things are going to be stuff like a solid jack, jack stands, a decent socket set and rust penetrant such as PB blaster. But I don't really want to seem like the authority on the matter here, I'm still learning and acquiring what I need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take it from chris fix if you want a full list of tools: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rCOgrIPFxIY"&gt;What are the Best Tools for Fixing Cars at Home?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other logistical issues to figure out though besides just the tools. You need a work space. Some places may make it very difficult to do your own repairs which might leave you to reaching out to friends or finding somewhere you can do them. Keep in mind for some repairs you may have to leave your car overnight, so be prepared to have alternative transportation. However, for a lot of stuff you may not even need to lift the car up. There's stuff you can do even if it is limited, but I acknowledge that in some situations it may be really tricky to even do your own repairs. Luckily I have an engineer for a roommate so there's space and tools abound! Hopefully, you can find something that works for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Preparing for rust removal&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I started about 2 years ago, I've gained more confidence and experience in doing my own repairs. Given I had a free week to do so, I put together a list of maintenance items. I just finished replacing the wheel bearing, which I decided to do in the most systematic way for any repair I've done yet. It seemed fairly intimidating given the amount of hammering and rust I saw in the videos, but when I actually did it I couldn't believe I was able to drive to work the next day! Car work usually has a sneaky way of being harder than what you see in the videos though, which is why I went to the lengths I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided that for the next repair on the list, rust removal, that I wanted to use it as an example for this blog post. In order to be as successful as possible I decided to type some notes to keep handy during the actual procedure. This isn't necessary for every repair, but for some it can be super helpful in giving you the confidence to attack it, especially if it's going to take a while to finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step in that process was to find a video or set of videos to learn from. ChrisFix has a pretty decent video on rust repair that really lays out the whole process very well from start to finish, so it felt like a natural choice. I found his outline at the beginning very helpful in my own notes. (Ignore the WheelBearing heading, I just copy pasted the page I was using to take notes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Screenshot of Notes" src="https://putz.space/images/diy/how-to-diy-cars-notes2.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This later expanded into headings that would have all the more detailed steps that he elaborates on. For the finished notes, &lt;a href="https://putz.space/diy/rust-removal"&gt;click this link here&lt;/a&gt;. I wrote down each important detail that I would be asking myself as I'm going along with the list on my own. What grit sand paper will I need for each step? How do I actually sand and apply paint? Prior experience helped me think about some of the ways problems come up while doing a repair and to be ready to address them. Be specific, don't just say "Sand the rust", be sure to explain to yourself &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to sand the rust with &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my notes I started a document with the link to the video for future reference, the necessary tools and the list of steps to actually do the repair. For other repairs you'll probably want to add parts necessary to replace with prices or even the torque spec for each fastener that needs it. But for our example I only needed to know the steps and what to buy. If you do this for all repairs you'll have your own little wikipedia of car repairs to reference if you ever need to do it again, making the next time much more efficient! You can update it with whatever lessons you learned while doing it too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Doing the repair&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before publishing this I wanted to do the repair myself to make sure I'm not just an idiot spouting shit off that doesn't actually work. The first major change to my plan was that in the end, with the advisory of a car friend, that the rust on my door was way too much to bother sanding down. It's even bigger than what I found in the video I was working on, so I felt like that made sense. It would be so full of holes that there'd be nothing left to fill and paint! The risk that the rust will just come back made it not worth bothering to do, so in the end I've hunted down a door that I found at a used parts place which I'll be putting on instead that doesn't have any rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there was still some minor rust spots on my car that I ended up needing to address before they got bigger. They were all on the body under the bottom of all the doors except for the rear driverside one which actually was in really good shape. The notes I typed up were still very useful for this even though I ended up not needing to follow the sections on using body filler. It still laid out the basic process to follow with what I need to do to be successful. I took notes on parts that I had questions on or trouble with to help for the next time I do rust removal. At the end of the day the best way is to learn by doing though to add to your experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of this was probably that shocking or may have even been common sense for people who are already used to doing DIY stuff. This was basically a space for me to reflect on my own process and try to help others by going through a repair that anyone with a car might need to do. Hopefully it's been helpful for you!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diy"></category><category term="auto"></category></entry><entry><title>Groove Masta Putz - The Time It Takes</title><link href="https://putz.space/music/demos/the-time-it-takes" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-05-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-05-05:/music/demos/the-time-it-takes</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Space Skeleton Gif" src="https://putz.space/blog/covers/the-time-it-takes.gif" id="article-image" /&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://jjjjjjjjjjohn.tumblr.com/post/101986737985"&gt;img source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio controls id="player"&gt;
    &lt;source id="song" src="https://putz.space/music/demos/Groove Masta Putz - The Time It Takes.mp3" type="audio/mp3" /&gt;
    Your browser does not support the audio tag. See below for direct link.
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://putz.space/music/demos/Groove Masta Putz - The Time It Takes.mp3"&gt;&lt;img alt="Direct link" src="https://putz.space/images/icons/download.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Played on the Casio before going to bed. There's not enough time in the day. So I played in the night. Headphones encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Music licensed under the &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"&gt;Creative Commons 4.0 - Attribution license&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Space Skeleton Gif" src="https://putz.space/blog/covers/the-time-it-takes.gif" id="article-image" /&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://jjjjjjjjjjohn.tumblr.com/post/101986737985"&gt;img source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio controls id="player"&gt;
    &lt;source id="song" src="https://putz.space/music/demos/Groove Masta Putz - The Time It Takes.mp3" type="audio/mp3" /&gt;
    Your browser does not support the audio tag. See below for direct link.
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://putz.space/music/demos/Groove Masta Putz - The Time It Takes.mp3"&gt;&lt;img alt="Direct link" src="https://putz.space/images/icons/download.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Played on the Casio before going to bed. There's not enough time in the day. So I played in the night. Headphones encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Music licensed under the &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"&gt;Creative Commons 4.0 - Attribution license&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="music"></category><category term="demo"></category></entry><entry><title>True Delusions - Song for Judee Sill and Other Songs</title><link href="https://putz.space/blog/true-delusions-judee-still/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-04T01:36:15-05:00</published><updated>2019-05-04T01:36:15-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-05-04:/blog/true-delusions-judee-still/</id><summary type="html">&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3038487279/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/artwork=small/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://truedelusions.bandcamp.com/album/song-for-judee-sill-and-other-songs"&gt;Song for Judee Sill and Other Songs by True Delusions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Embedded for your listening pleasure as you read this review. Link below if it doesn't work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the course of asking people what they'd like to see on the blog, Justin Haze of &lt;a href="https://truedelusions.bandcamp.com/"&gt;True Delusions&lt;/a&gt; reached out asking if I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3038487279/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/artwork=small/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://truedelusions.bandcamp.com/album/song-for-judee-sill-and-other-songs"&gt;Song for Judee Sill and Other Songs by True Delusions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Embedded for your listening pleasure as you read this review. Link below if it doesn't work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the course of asking people what they'd like to see on the blog, Justin Haze of &lt;a href="https://truedelusions.bandcamp.com/"&gt;True Delusions&lt;/a&gt; reached out asking if I could review his album. Truth be told I've never done such a thing, but I decided  why not! To disclose my own biases at the start I usually don't listen to that much indie-rock style stuff, but it's not absent from my library either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, now that that's out of the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we first enter the world of True Delusions we're greeted with a bouncing beat that quickly explodes into the distorted chug of a cheery electric guitar and dreamy vocals that hovers between story and melody. The themes I piece together from the instruments and vocals is about love, sex and life to the sounds of rock n roll. In many ways the chaotic distortion and story actually fits together nicely to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the album goes on it takes a more subdued path that becomes even trippier. I'll admit I'm already bad with following lyrics, so I'm not sure if the vocals contradict with the feeling I get from them at all, but I get a sense of longing, misunderstanding and reality bending under pressure. When things are more positive and uplifting, I'm struck with a feeling of confidence and purpose that is reflected in the clarity and power of the vocals and the uplifting energy the drums &amp;amp; guitar provides. When things feel more subdued and sad, I feel the sense of confusion and meloncholy. I like how it oscillates between the sadder tones while moving back to optimistic tones and upbeat energy in the cyclical way that love and life often does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole album feels metaphoric and poetic. What I find particularly relatable, personally, is using music as a way to understand your own feelings and as a form of therapy, which I get a sense of while I listen to this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was actually surprised with the album as a whole. I'll admit some songs don't resonate with me in the way that it might for others who are in the emotional space to vibe with them, but other songs are actually really well done and I like them quite a bit. Some of my personal favorites include: I Unloaded Them And Dropped 'Em, Candle Lit, Are Distorting Again, Old Earth Angel and Thanks With Many Breaths. Not that I would say the others were "bad", but I just dug the vibe more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I particularly like how the guitar throughout the album is twisted and distorted in subtle, yet dope ways. Indie-rock can be an easy sound to get lost in irrelevance to without making your sound distinct, so that and the subtlety of the synths and effects were well done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm impressed by how professional the album sounds and seeing Justin's work develop and grow like this is quite cool. A big difference is probably due to this being recorded in an actual studio versus what I'm assuming was home equipment from songs I've heard in the past. I'm impressed how it still captures the distorted, chaotic feel of his old work while sounding well-mastered and crisp in a refined way that shows how much effort has gone into this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congrats on finishing the album dude!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="music"></category><category term="review"></category></entry><entry><title>Groove Masta Putz - Forward</title><link href="https://putz.space/music/demos/forward" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-04-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-04-17:/music/demos/forward</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Casio CTK-720" src="https://putz.space/blog/covers/casio.jpg" id="article-image" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio controls id="player"&gt;
    &lt;source id="song" src="https://putz.space/music/demos/Groove Masta Putz - Forward.mp3" type="audio/mp3" /&gt;
    Your browser does not support the audio tag. See below for direct link.
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://putz.space/music/demos/Groove Masta Putz - Forward.mp3"&gt;&lt;img alt="Direct link" src="https://putz.space/images/icons/download.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New beat! This one is a little old, but since I haven't had an outlet to post music to I haven't really put it out there. It's called "Forward", because that's what I was feeling in my …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Casio CTK-720" src="https://putz.space/blog/covers/casio.jpg" id="article-image" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio controls id="player"&gt;
    &lt;source id="song" src="https://putz.space/music/demos/Groove Masta Putz - Forward.mp3" type="audio/mp3" /&gt;
    Your browser does not support the audio tag. See below for direct link.
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://putz.space/music/demos/Groove Masta Putz - Forward.mp3"&gt;&lt;img alt="Direct link" src="https://putz.space/images/icons/download.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New beat! This one is a little old, but since I haven't had an outlet to post music to I haven't really put it out there. It's called "Forward", because that's what I was feeling in my life at the time (and still feel). Recorded with my Casio CTK-720, which is the derpy piano I got in middle school that's pictured above. Used renoise to mix, master and add the bass &amp;amp; strings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Music licensed under the &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"&gt;Creative Commons 4.0 - Attribution license&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="music"></category><category term="demo"></category></entry><entry><title>Returning to Facebook</title><link href="https://putz.space/blog/returning-to-facebook/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-13T19:58:10-05:00</published><updated>2019-04-13T19:58:10-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-04-13:/blog/returning-to-facebook/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm curious who out there were placing bets on when I'd be back on facebook lol. Well, I made a pretty big stink when I left, so I wrote up a blog post to explain why I'm back because I'm sure everyone is as shocked as I am (or not lol). I was on Mastodon and Reddit, but nobody I know really uses them so I figured I'd come back. Most of you are on here and the people is what makes social media meaningful. So what up what up yo.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Facebook banner" src="https://putz.space/blog/covers/returning-to-facebook.png" id="article-image" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after a long break from Facebook I'm finally back again to the shock of everyone lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I originally deleted Facebook (the first time), I got a bunch of friend's email addresses hoping to stay in touch directly. However, that never happened because quite frankly there's just too many people to stay in touch with and not enough time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I also just needed some time to focus on myself. I was addicted to the notifications that kept me in a loop of constantly rechecking, without thinking, any time I was remotely bored and needed something to keep me busy. I would immediately type out "facebook.com" into my browser and it would suck up a lot of valuable free time without actually feeling connected to people. So I got rid of it. I opened and deleted a Facebook account here or there a few more times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time, I decided to reopen it for promoting my music, but really just used that to talk about politics all the time. I also became increasingly concerned with how it spies on us and the implications that will have politically in the future, but now that everything spies on us all the time it feels like a moot point. As an ironic joke ask an Alexa, Siri or Google "What is 1984 by George Orwell?" then record it and share its response, just curious what it says lol. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, leaving was good for me because it allowed me the space to focus on myself. I focused more on my to-do list, journaling and setting personal goals that I would look at when I was bored instead of Facebook. I recommend this to anyone who feels like they're in a rut and I might write something up in a future blog post about my own personal methods of doing this. It has allowed me to control myself better and has given me mental tools to stay focused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was good for a time, but lately I've started to feel the alienation that comes with being disconnected from so many people I used to talk to. The community-based alternatives on the &lt;a href="https://fediverse.party/en/fediverse/"&gt;fediverse&lt;/a&gt; like &lt;a href="http://joinmastodon.org"&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; are cool and show what's possible for social media in the future, but nobody I know is on them yet so they're a bit lonely. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm back because, well frankly, I miss you guys and seeing where you're at in life. Now that I'm an adult, life is a lot busier and I'm sure many of you can relate. Lots of old friends I used to be in touch with are off on adventures in different parts of the world, or paying bills and adulting with actual children that y'all are now raising. Crazy stuff!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What finally pushed me over the edge to hop back on Facebook though was: on reddit I saw a comment thread on one of the many articles regarding &lt;a href="https://www.latimes.com/politics/la-na-pol-trump-migrants-sanctuary-cities-20190412-story.html"&gt;Trump's plan to drop off immigrants into sanctuary cities&lt;/a&gt; as... a punishment to the Democrats I guess? I mean shit, those families would happily leave the cages they're in and most people in the comments wanted to welcome them to their community anyway. That's a reflection of the moment we live in. Where it seems like things are so goddamn bad, but actually the potential to make it better is bustling beneath the seams ready to explode because people know things should be better than this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we need right now is community that can support one another in the face of being torn apart by whatever storm society is going through. So I wanted to reconnect with mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Putz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S: I started my own website again, which you're on right now. More on that here: &lt;a href="https://putz.space/blog/hello-world/"&gt;Hello World!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>Hello World!</title><link href="https://putz.space/blog/hello-world/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-03T23:08:53-05:00</published><updated>2019-04-03T23:08:53-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-04-03:/blog/hello-world/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone! So it's probably been a while since you've heard from me because I dropped off of facebook and started interacting way less with social media. For many people reading this we probably haven't talked since I was in college. Even if we have, it probably hasn't been as …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone! So it's probably been a while since you've heard from me because I dropped off of facebook and started interacting way less with social media. For many people reading this we probably haven't talked since I was in college. Even if we have, it probably hasn't been as frequently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've decided to start this website as one way for people to see what I'm up to. I realize this probably won't be something most people come back to regularly, if at all, but since you're reading this I figured I'd let you know what I'm up to anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought &lt;a href="#"&gt;putz.space&lt;/a&gt; as a way to have a consistent email since I finally decided to switch away from gmail as my primary email. Check the &lt;a href="https://putz.space/about/"&gt;about&lt;/a&gt; page if you want to send me an email or connect on social media. You can still technically reach me at my old email, it just might get lost with all the unread emails lol. After buying a domain name though, it was a logical next step to start a website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually had a website back in middle and high school that I worked on as a hobby for myself. I'd like to do that again. I want it to be the central place where you can go to see what I'm up to. In fact, if you want me to link to what &lt;em&gt;you're&lt;/em&gt; doing, then let me know and I can make a page for my friends who are doing cool shit too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing that made the most sense to me is obviously hosting my music, because I am Groove Masta Putz after all lol. In fact, if you're interested in a mailing list for any new tracks, &lt;a href="mailto:inbox@putz.space"&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt; and I'll add you for when I actually make one in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I've also been trying to think of what else might be interesting to people. So another thing I'd like to try is write up tutorials and other useful posts for stuff that can guide people through some things that I've done like: make this website, how I organize my life, how to follow news sources without Facebook or Reddit, or how to hack your wii to play all the dope old school games and much more. If there's something else you'd like to see let me know! Ideas are welcome and they don't have to be nerd shit either necessarily. I just want to motivate myself to do cool things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm still figuring this out as I go, but I'm trying to think big. The most exciting thing to me is having an online space again that's mine. With facebook and other social media I no longer felt like the people I care about were seeing me behind all the ads and secret algorithms. Plus, it was limited and a full website gives me more control over what I can host and how. For example, I can take my &lt;a href="https://putz.space/music/"&gt;music&lt;/a&gt; page more seriously and get in-depth about each song and its history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a lot more I want to say, but I guess that's what future blog posts will be for. Hope y'all are doing well out there, it's a crazy world these days. Definitely weird to be an adult now, but that's just how it be, huh. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to say hi if we haven't talked in a while!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>Update - added music section</title><link href="https://putz.space/blog/2019-02-31-update-music/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-21T00:42:43-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-21T00:42:43-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-03-21:/blog/2019-02-31-update-music/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After a day of putting it all together, I've finally got the music section in a workable state! I'm still not 100% finished with it, I'd like to add some descriptions for each song individually and see if there's a way to make the music player play through the whole …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After a day of putting it all together, I've finally got the music section in a workable state! I'm still not 100% finished with it, I'd like to add some descriptions for each song individually and see if there's a way to make the music player play through the whole album (just plays one song and stops atm). That and I need to figure out the best way to approach direct downloads, but for now other sites where you can find them are up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://putz.space/music/"&gt;Go check it out!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="music"></category></entry><entry><title>Updates</title><link href="https://putz.space/blog/2019-03-18-updates/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-18T01:22:03-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-18T01:22:03-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-03-18:/blog/2019-03-18-updates/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Been working on the stylesheet all night and I think it's in a place where the experience should hopefully be a little better finally, especially for mobile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically the only thing I have to do now is set up a system for making posts (or just learning Markdown and type …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Been working on the stylesheet all night and I think it's in a place where the experience should hopefully be a little better finally, especially for mobile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically the only thing I have to do now is set up a system for making posts (or just learning Markdown and type it up in a text editor I guess like a nerd lol), figure out how I want to host my music and I think from there most of the setup should be done. Anyway, hopefully this will be the start a of a long fruitful journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll see if it's worth it to do blogging or not. You can catch me on other social media found either in the &lt;a href="../pages/about.html"&gt;about&lt;/a&gt; page or in the footer for the real shitposts though lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS, just discovered &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sCNlt5nvSI8"&gt;FKJ&lt;/a&gt;. Go check him out he's good shit!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>Website launch</title><link href="https://putz.space/blog/website-launch/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-03-12:/blog/website-launch/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well hello there! I'm starting a website because I want to have a place where 
people can stay in touch with me and see what I'm up to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just recently switched to pelican to run things because it offers more
powerful tools for running a blog than &lt;a href="http://zim-wiki.org"&gt;zim-wiki&lt;/a&gt;, which …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well hello there! I'm starting a website because I want to have a place where 
people can stay in touch with me and see what I'm up to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just recently switched to pelican to run things because it offers more
powerful tools for running a blog than &lt;a href="http://zim-wiki.org"&gt;zim-wiki&lt;/a&gt;, which I use for taking notes
and keeping track of other stuff in my life. It can technically also publish
websites, but it's kinda limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is the first blog post, testing that out! I'll be adding more as I go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working on the CSS so it looks a little better and stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category></entry></feed>