<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>putz.space</title><link href="https://putz.space/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://putz.space/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://putz.space/</id><updated>2019-03-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Update - added music section</title><link href="https://putz.space/update-added-music-section.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-03-19:/update-added-music-section.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After a day of putting it all together, I've finally got the music section in a workable state! I'm still not 100% finished with it, I'd like to add some descriptions for each song individually and see if there's a way to make the music player play through the whole …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After a day of putting it all together, I've finally got the music section in a workable state! I'm still not 100% finished with it, I'd like to add some descriptions for each song individually and see if there's a way to make the music player play through the whole album (just plays one song and stops atm). That and I need to figure out the best way to approach direct downloads, but for now other sites where you can find them are up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://putz.space/pages/music.html"&gt;Go check it out!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="music"></category></entry><entry><title>Updates</title><link href="https://putz.space/2019-03-18-updates.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-03-18:/2019-03-18-updates.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Been working on the stylesheet all night and I think it's in a place where the experience should hopefully be a little better finally, especially for mobile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically the only thing I have to do now is set up a system for making posts (or just learning Markdown and type …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Been working on the stylesheet all night and I think it's in a place where the experience should hopefully be a little better finally, especially for mobile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically the only thing I have to do now is set up a system for making posts (or just learning Markdown and type it up in a text editor I guess like a nerd lol), figure out how I want to host my music and I think from there most of the setup should be done. Anyway, hopefully this will be the start a of a long fruitful journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll see if it's worth it to do blogging or not. You can catch me on other social media found either in the &lt;a href="../pages/about.html"&gt;about&lt;/a&gt; page or in the footer for the real shitposts though lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS, just discovered &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sCNlt5nvSI8"&gt;FKJ&lt;/a&gt;. Go check him out he's good shit!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>Website launch</title><link href="https://putz.space/2019-03-12-website-launch.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-03-12:/2019-03-12-website-launch.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well hello there! I'm starting a website because I want to have a place where 
people can stay in touch with me and see what I'm up to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just recently switched to pelican to run things because it offers more
powerful tools for running a blog than &lt;a href="http://zim-wiki.org"&gt;zim-wiki&lt;/a&gt;, which …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well hello there! I'm starting a website because I want to have a place where 
people can stay in touch with me and see what I'm up to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just recently switched to pelican to run things because it offers more
powerful tools for running a blog than &lt;a href="http://zim-wiki.org"&gt;zim-wiki&lt;/a&gt;, which I use for taking notes
and keeping track of other stuff in my life. It can technically also publish
websites, but it's kinda limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is the first blog post, testing that out! I'll be adding more as I go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working on the CSS so it looks a little better and stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category></entry></feed>