<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>putz.space</title><link href="https://putz.space/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://putz.space/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://putz.space/</id><updated>2019-05-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Groove Masta Putz - Morning Rise</title><link href="https://putz.space/music/demos/morning-rise/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-05-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-05-18:/music/demos/morning-rise/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Futuristic Society Man" src="https://putz.space/blog/covers/morning-rise.jpg" id="article-image" /&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://ccsearch.creativecommons.org/photos/ddd846a6-3c34-4dc7-9e72-af0486a29df4"&gt;img source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio controls id="player"&gt;
    &lt;source id="song" src="https://putz.space/music/demos/Groove Masta Putz - Morning Rise.mp3" type="audio/mp3" /&gt;
    Your browser does not support the audio tag. See below for direct link.
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://putz.space/music/demos/Groove Masta Putz - Morning Rise.mp3"&gt;&lt;img alt="Direct link" src="https://putz.space/images/icons/download.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/groovemastaputz/groove-masta-putz-morning-rise"&gt;&lt;img alt="SoundCloud" src="https://putz.space/images/icons/soundcloud.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.newgrounds.com/audio/listen/863766"&gt;&lt;img alt="Newgrounds" src="https://putz.space/images/icons/newgrounds.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woke up this morning and decided go on a musical journey until I came up with this demo. Could expand later, but in the meantime let this take you on a journey through... T H …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Futuristic Society Man" src="https://putz.space/blog/covers/morning-rise.jpg" id="article-image" /&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://ccsearch.creativecommons.org/photos/ddd846a6-3c34-4dc7-9e72-af0486a29df4"&gt;img source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio controls id="player"&gt;
    &lt;source id="song" src="https://putz.space/music/demos/Groove Masta Putz - Morning Rise.mp3" type="audio/mp3" /&gt;
    Your browser does not support the audio tag. See below for direct link.
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://putz.space/music/demos/Groove Masta Putz - Morning Rise.mp3"&gt;&lt;img alt="Direct link" src="https://putz.space/images/icons/download.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/groovemastaputz/groove-masta-putz-morning-rise"&gt;&lt;img alt="SoundCloud" src="https://putz.space/images/icons/soundcloud.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.newgrounds.com/audio/listen/863766"&gt;&lt;img alt="Newgrounds" src="https://putz.space/images/icons/newgrounds.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woke up this morning and decided go on a musical journey until I came up with this demo. Could expand later, but in the meantime let this take you on a journey through... T H E F U T U R E.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Music licensed under the &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"&gt;Creative Commons 4.0 - Attribution license&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="music"></category><category term="demo"></category></entry><entry><title>How I learned DIY auto repair</title><link href="https://putz.space/2019/05/16/diy-car-repair/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-16T22:15:57-05:00</published><updated>2019-05-16T22:15:57-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-05-16:/2019/05/16/diy-car-repair/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ever since dealing with a crap car, it became clear I needed to learn more about cars. So here's how I did that! I focused on the process because there's already plenty of resources out there for specific repairs. I felt it would be helpful to look at how I prepared to do rust removal on my car as an example to share. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Derpy car" src="https://putz.space/blog/covers/diy-car-repair.png" width="400px" height="250px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fuckin' cars...&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let's make a long story short. I had an ok car that was high maintenance. It sucked. I decided that I was done dealing with the anxiety of what they're gonna find at the shop next. I was sick of wondering if the noises I hear from my car were normal or not. That lead me on my journey to finally learn what the hell is going on inside my car because until public transit is faster than 1.5hr each way to work, I'm gonna have to rely on one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;First steps&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing that you have to do before you can learn about any subject is how to speak the lingo. So I set out to learn the basics about car anatomy and terminology. What is each part called. What's a bearing? Why is it so expensive to repair a head gasket? What is that anyway? Stuff like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need somewhere to start you can always ask any mechanic buddies and see what they would say. Most will probably say they learned from an uncle or someone, so they can maybe help you out actually doing the repair if they're willing to take the time out of their day to do it (compensation helps). But online there are plenty of videos and I personally like reading so I found books to be very helpful as well. Something as simple as "Car Repair for Dummies" was actually quite foundational in explaining what everything is called and their place in your car's system. If you're a woman there are even books written by other women who speak to the particularities of car repair from a woman's perspective (like say, maybe dealing with assholes who don't take you seriously). Maybe there's community college classes. Find what speaks to you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some youtube channels I like, however you may have to search for stuff particular to your car because everyone has different vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/PaintballOO7"&gt;ChrisFix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/EricTheCarGuy"&gt;Eric the Car Guy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCT5dv3iwFuy041dbWPB6skg"&gt;Ratchets and Wrenches&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/1aauto"&gt;1A Auto Parts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don't have to go too deep though to find a lot useful information. If you really don't have the time to get a degree in cars then just take note of anything you have questions about while watching youtube videos and search any terms as you get stuck. This knowledge will accumulate over time even if the initial time investment may be a bit high at first. At the very least, you'll get an idea whether you need to take it in or if you can do it yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point is though, you need to figure out &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; you need to know and &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to learn it. Apply that to life!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Getting the tools&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step is to get any tools you'll need to actually apply that knowledge in the real world. The most essential things are going to be stuff like a solid jack, jack stands, a decent socket set and rust penetrant such as PB blaster. But I don't really want to seem like the authority on the matter here, I'm still learning and acquiring what I need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take it from chris fix if you want a full list of tools: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rCOgrIPFxIY"&gt;What are the Best Tools for Fixing Cars at Home?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other logistical issues to figure out though besides just the tools. You need a work space. Some places may make it very difficult to do your own repairs which might leave you to reaching out to friends or finding somewhere you can do them. Keep in mind for some repairs you may have to leave your car overnight, so be prepared to have alternative transportation. However, for a lot of stuff you may not even need to lift the car up. There's stuff you can do even if it is limited, but I acknowledge that in some situations it may be really tricky to even do your own repairs. Luckily I have an engineer for a roommate so there's space and tools abound! Hopefully, you can find something that works for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Preparing for rust removal&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I started about 2 years ago, I've gained more confidence and experience in doing my own repairs. Given I had a free week to do so, I put together a list of maintenance items. I just finished replacing the wheel bearing, which I decided to do in the most systematic way for any repair I've done yet. It seemed fairly intimidating given the amount of hammering and rust I saw in the videos, but when I actually did it I couldn't believe I was able to drive to work the next day! Car work usually has a sneaky way of being harder than what you see in the videos though, which is why I went to the lengths I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided that for the next repair on the list, rust removal, that I wanted to use it as an example for this blog post. In order to be as successful as possible I decided to type some notes to keep handy during the actual procedure. This isn't necessary for every repair, but for some it can be super helpful in giving you the confidence to attack it, especially if it's going to take a while to finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step in that process was to find a video or set of videos to learn from. ChrisFix has a pretty decent video on rust repair that really lays out the whole process very well from start to finish, so it felt like a natural choice. I found his outline at the beginning very helpful in my own notes. (Ignore the WheelBearing heading, I just copy pasted the page I was using to take notes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Screenshot of Notes" src="https://putz.space/images/diy/how-to-diy-cars-notes2.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This later expanded into headings that would have all the more detailed steps that he elaborates on. For the finished notes, &lt;a href="https://putz.space/diy/rust-removal"&gt;click this link here&lt;/a&gt;. I wrote down each important detail that I would be asking myself as I'm going along with the list on my own. What grit sand paper will I need for each step? How do I actually sand and apply paint? Prior experience helped me think about some of the ways problems come up while doing a repair and to be ready to address them. Be specific, don't just say "Sand the rust", be sure to explain to yourself &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to sand the rust with &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my notes I started a document with the link to the video for future reference, the necessary tools and the list of steps to actually do the repair. For other repairs you'll probably want to add parts necessary to replace with prices or even the torque spec for each fastener that needs it. But for our example I only needed to know the steps and what to buy. If you do this for all repairs you'll have your own little wikipedia of car repairs to reference if you ever need to do it again, making the next time much more efficient! You can update it with whatever lessons you learned while doing it too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Doing the repair&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before publishing this I wanted to do the repair myself to make sure I'm not just an idiot spouting shit off that doesn't actually work. The first major change to my plan was that in the end, with the advisory of a car friend, that the rust on my door was way too much to bother sanding down. It's even bigger than what I found in the video I was working on, so I felt like that made sense. It would be so full of holes that there'd be nothing left to fill and paint! The risk that the rust will just come back made it not worth bothering to do, so in the end I've hunted down a door that I found at a used parts place which I'll be putting on instead that doesn't have any rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there was still some minor rust spots on my car that I ended up needing to address before they got bigger. They were all on the body under the bottom of all the doors except for the rear driverside one which actually was in really good shape. The notes I typed up were still very useful for this even though I ended up not needing to follow the sections on using body filler. It still laid out the basic process to follow with what I need to do to be successful. I took notes on parts that I had questions on or trouble with to help for the next time I do rust removal. At the end of the day the best way is to learn by doing though to add to your experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of this was probably that shocking or may have even been common sense for people who are already used to doing DIY stuff. This was basically a space for me to reflect on my own process and try to help others by going through a repair that anyone with a car might need to do. Hopefully it's been helpful for you!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diy"></category><category term="auto"></category></entry><entry><title>Groove Masta Putz - The Time It Takes</title><link href="https://putz.space/music/demos/the-time-it-takes" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-05-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-05-05:/music/demos/the-time-it-takes</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Space Skeleton Gif" src="https://putz.space/blog/covers/the-time-it-takes.gif" id="article-image" /&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://jjjjjjjjjjohn.tumblr.com/post/101986737985"&gt;img source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio controls id="player"&gt;
    &lt;source id="song" src="https://putz.space/music/demos/Groove Masta Putz - The Time It Takes.mp3" type="audio/mp3" /&gt;
    Your browser does not support the audio tag. See below for direct link.
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://putz.space/music/demos/Groove Masta Putz - The Time It Takes.mp3"&gt;&lt;img alt="Direct link" src="https://putz.space/images/icons/download.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Played on the Casio before going to bed. There's not enough time in the day. So I played in the night. Headphones encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Music licensed under the &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"&gt;Creative Commons 4.0 - Attribution license&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Space Skeleton Gif" src="https://putz.space/blog/covers/the-time-it-takes.gif" id="article-image" /&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://jjjjjjjjjjohn.tumblr.com/post/101986737985"&gt;img source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio controls id="player"&gt;
    &lt;source id="song" src="https://putz.space/music/demos/Groove Masta Putz - The Time It Takes.mp3" type="audio/mp3" /&gt;
    Your browser does not support the audio tag. See below for direct link.
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://putz.space/music/demos/Groove Masta Putz - The Time It Takes.mp3"&gt;&lt;img alt="Direct link" src="https://putz.space/images/icons/download.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Played on the Casio before going to bed. There's not enough time in the day. So I played in the night. Headphones encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Music licensed under the &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"&gt;Creative Commons 4.0 - Attribution license&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="music"></category><category term="demo"></category></entry><entry><title>True Delusions - Song for Judee Sill and Other Songs</title><link href="https://putz.space/2019/05/04/true-delusions-judee-still/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-04T01:36:15-05:00</published><updated>2019-05-04T01:36:15-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-05-04:/2019/05/04/true-delusions-judee-still/</id><summary type="html">&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3038487279/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/artwork=small/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://truedelusions.bandcamp.com/album/song-for-judee-sill-and-other-songs"&gt;Song for Judee Sill and Other Songs by True Delusions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Embedded for your listening pleasure as you read this review. Link below if it doesn't work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the course of asking people what they'd like to see on the blog, Justin Haze of &lt;a href="https://truedelusions.bandcamp.com/"&gt;True Delusions&lt;/a&gt; reached out asking if I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3038487279/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/artwork=small/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://truedelusions.bandcamp.com/album/song-for-judee-sill-and-other-songs"&gt;Song for Judee Sill and Other Songs by True Delusions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Embedded for your listening pleasure as you read this review. Link below if it doesn't work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the course of asking people what they'd like to see on the blog, Justin Haze of &lt;a href="https://truedelusions.bandcamp.com/"&gt;True Delusions&lt;/a&gt; reached out asking if I could review his album. Truth be told I've never done such a thing, but I decided  why not! To disclose my own biases at the start I usually don't listen to that much indie-rock style stuff, but it's not absent from my library either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, now that that's out of the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we first enter the world of True Delusions we're greeted with a bouncing beat that quickly explodes into the distorted chug of a cheery electric guitar and dreamy vocals that hovers between story and melody. The themes I piece together from the instruments and vocals is about love, sex and life to the sounds of rock n roll. In many ways the chaotic distortion and story actually fits together nicely to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the album goes on it takes a more subdued path that becomes even trippier. I'll admit I'm already bad with following lyrics, so I'm not sure if the vocals contradict with the feeling I get from them at all, but I get a sense of longing, misunderstanding and reality bending under pressure. When things are more positive and uplifting, I'm struck with a feeling of confidence and purpose that is reflected in the clarity and power of the vocals and the uplifting energy the drums &amp;amp; guitar provides. When things feel more subdued and sad, I feel the sense of confusion and meloncholy. I like how it oscillates between the sadder tones while moving back to optimistic tones and upbeat energy in the cyclical way that love and life often does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole album feels metaphoric and poetic. What I find particularly relatable, personally, is using music as a way to understand your own feelings and as a form of therapy, which I get a sense of while I listen to this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was actually surprised with the album as a whole. I'll admit some songs don't resonate with me in the way that it might for others who are in the emotional space to vibe with them, but other songs are actually really well done and I like them quite a bit. Some of my personal favorites include: I Unloaded Them And Dropped 'Em, Candle Lit, Are Distorting Again, Old Earth Angel and Thanks With Many Breaths. Not that I would say the others were "bad", but I just dug the vibe more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I particularly like how the guitar throughout the album is twisted and distorted in subtle, yet dope ways. Indie-rock can be an easy sound to get lost in irrelevance to without making your sound distinct, so that and the subtlety of the synths and effects were well done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm impressed by how professional the album sounds and seeing Justin's work develop and grow like this is quite cool. A big difference is probably due to this being recorded in an actual studio versus what I'm assuming was home equipment from songs I've heard in the past. I'm impressed how it still captures the distorted, chaotic feel of his old work while sounding well-mastered and crisp in a refined way that shows how much effort has gone into this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congrats on finishing the album dude!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="music"></category><category term="review"></category></entry><entry><title>Groove Masta Putz - Forward</title><link href="https://putz.space/music/demos/forward" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-04-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-04-17:/music/demos/forward</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Casio CTK-720" src="https://putz.space/blog/covers/casio.jpg" id="article-image" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio controls id="player"&gt;
    &lt;source id="song" src="https://putz.space/music/demos/Groove Masta Putz - Forward.mp3" type="audio/mp3" /&gt;
    Your browser does not support the audio tag. See below for direct link.
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://putz.space/music/demos/Groove Masta Putz - Forward.mp3"&gt;&lt;img alt="Direct link" src="https://putz.space/images/icons/download.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New beat! This one is a little old, but since I haven't had an outlet to post music to I haven't really put it out there. It's called "Forward", because that's what I was feeling in my …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Casio CTK-720" src="https://putz.space/blog/covers/casio.jpg" id="article-image" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio controls id="player"&gt;
    &lt;source id="song" src="https://putz.space/music/demos/Groove Masta Putz - Forward.mp3" type="audio/mp3" /&gt;
    Your browser does not support the audio tag. See below for direct link.
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://putz.space/music/demos/Groove Masta Putz - Forward.mp3"&gt;&lt;img alt="Direct link" src="https://putz.space/images/icons/download.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New beat! This one is a little old, but since I haven't had an outlet to post music to I haven't really put it out there. It's called "Forward", because that's what I was feeling in my life at the time (and still feel). Recorded with my Casio CTK-720, which is the derpy piano I got in middle school that's pictured above. Used renoise to mix, master and add the bass &amp;amp; strings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Music licensed under the &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"&gt;Creative Commons 4.0 - Attribution license&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="music"></category><category term="demo"></category></entry><entry><title>Returning to Facebook</title><link href="https://putz.space/2019/04/13/returning-to-facebook/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-13T19:58:10-05:00</published><updated>2019-04-13T19:58:10-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-04-13:/2019/04/13/returning-to-facebook/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm curious who out there were placing bets on when I'd be back on facebook lol. Well, I made a pretty big stink when I left, so I wrote up a blog post to explain why I'm back because I'm sure everyone is as shocked as I am (or not lol). I was on Mastodon and Reddit, but nobody I know really uses them so I figured I'd come back. Most of you are on here and the people is what makes social media meaningful. So what up what up yo.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Facebook banner" src="https://putz.space/blog/covers/returning-to-facebook.png" id="article-image" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after a long break from Facebook I'm finally back again to the shock of everyone lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I originally deleted Facebook (the first time), I got a bunch of friend's email addresses hoping to stay in touch directly. However, that never happened because quite frankly there's just too many people to stay in touch with and not enough time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I also just needed some time to focus on myself. I was addicted to the notifications that kept me in a loop of constantly rechecking, without thinking, any time I was remotely bored and needed something to keep me busy. I would immediately type out "facebook.com" into my browser and it would suck up a lot of valuable free time without actually feeling connected to people. So I got rid of it. I opened and deleted a Facebook account here or there a few more times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time, I decided to reopen it for promoting my music, but really just used that to talk about politics all the time. I also became increasingly concerned with how it spies on us and the implications that will have politically in the future, but now that everything spies on us all the time it feels like a moot point. As an ironic joke ask an Alexa, Siri or Google "What is 1984 by George Orwell?" then record it and share its response, just curious what it says lol. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, leaving was good for me because it allowed me the space to focus on myself. I focused more on my to-do list, journaling and setting personal goals that I would look at when I was bored instead of Facebook. I recommend this to anyone who feels like they're in a rut and I might write something up in a future blog post about my own personal methods of doing this. It has allowed me to control myself better and has given me mental tools to stay focused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was good for a time, but lately I've started to feel the alienation that comes with being disconnected from so many people I used to talk to. The community-based alternatives on the &lt;a href="https://fediverse.party/en/fediverse/"&gt;fediverse&lt;/a&gt; like &lt;a href="http://joinmastodon.org"&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; are cool and show what's possible for social media in the future, but nobody I know is on them yet so they're a bit lonely. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm back because, well frankly, I miss you guys and seeing where you're at in life. Now that I'm an adult, life is a lot busier and I'm sure many of you can relate. Lots of old friends I used to be in touch with are off on adventures in different parts of the world, or paying bills and adulting with actual children that y'all are now raising. Crazy stuff!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What finally pushed me over the edge to hop back on Facebook though was: on reddit I saw a comment thread on one of the many articles regarding &lt;a href="https://www.latimes.com/politics/la-na-pol-trump-migrants-sanctuary-cities-20190412-story.html"&gt;Trump's plan to drop off immigrants into sanctuary cities&lt;/a&gt; as... a punishment to the Democrats I guess? I mean shit, those families would happily leave the cages they're in and most people in the comments wanted to welcome them to their community anyway. That's a reflection of the moment we live in. Where it seems like things are so goddamn bad, but actually the potential to make it better is bustling beneath the seams ready to explode because people know things should be better than this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we need right now is community that can support one another in the face of being torn apart by whatever storm society is going through. So I wanted to reconnect with mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Putz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S: I started my own website again, which you're on right now. More on that here: &lt;a href="https://putz.space/2019/04/03/hello-world/"&gt;Hello World!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>Hello World!</title><link href="https://putz.space/2019/04/03/hello-world/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-03T23:08:53-05:00</published><updated>2019-04-03T23:08:53-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-04-03:/2019/04/03/hello-world/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone! So it's probably been a while since you've heard from me because I dropped off of facebook and started interacting way less with social media. For many people reading this we probably haven't talked since I was in college. Even if we have, it probably hasn't been as …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone! So it's probably been a while since you've heard from me because I dropped off of facebook and started interacting way less with social media. For many people reading this we probably haven't talked since I was in college. Even if we have, it probably hasn't been as frequently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've decided to start this website as one way for people to see what I'm up to. I realize this probably won't be something most people come back to regularly, if at all, but since you're reading this I figured I'd let you know what I'm up to anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought &lt;a href="#"&gt;putz.space&lt;/a&gt; as a way to have a consistent email since I finally decided to switch away from gmail as my primary email. Check the &lt;a href="https://putz.space/about/"&gt;about&lt;/a&gt; page if you want to send me an email or connect on social media. You can still technically reach me at my old email, it just might get lost with all the unread emails lol. After buying a domain name though, it was a logical next step to start a website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually had a website back in middle and high school that I worked on as a hobby for myself. I'd like to do that again. I want it to be the central place where you can go to see what I'm up to. In fact, if you want me to link to what &lt;em&gt;you're&lt;/em&gt; doing, then let me know and I can make a page for my friends who are doing cool shit too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing that made the most sense to me is obviously hosting my music, because I am Groove Masta Putz after all lol. In fact, if you're interested in a mailing list for any new tracks, &lt;a href="mailto:inbox@putz.space"&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt; and I'll add you for when I actually make one in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I've also been trying to think of what else might be interesting to people. So another thing I'd like to try is write up tutorials and other useful posts for stuff that can guide people through some things that I've done like: make this website, how I organize my life, how to follow news sources without Facebook or Reddit, or how to hack your wii to play all the dope old school games and much more. If there's something else you'd like to see let me know! Ideas are welcome and they don't have to be nerd shit either necessarily. I just want to motivate myself to do cool things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm still figuring this out as I go, but I'm trying to think big. The most exciting thing to me is having an online space again that's mine. With facebook and other social media I no longer felt like the people I care about were seeing me behind all the ads and secret algorithms. Plus, it was limited and a full website gives me more control over what I can host and how. For example, I can take my &lt;a href="https://putz.space/music/"&gt;music&lt;/a&gt; page more seriously and get in-depth about each song and its history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a lot more I want to say, but I guess that's what future blog posts will be for. Hope y'all are doing well out there, it's a crazy world these days. Definitely weird to be an adult now, but that's just how it be, huh. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to say hi if we haven't talked in a while!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>Update - added music section</title><link href="https://putz.space/2019/03/21/2019-02-31-update-music/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-21T00:42:43-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-21T00:42:43-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-03-21:/2019/03/21/2019-02-31-update-music/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After a day of putting it all together, I've finally got the music section in a workable state! I'm still not 100% finished with it, I'd like to add some descriptions for each song individually and see if there's a way to make the music player play through the whole …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After a day of putting it all together, I've finally got the music section in a workable state! I'm still not 100% finished with it, I'd like to add some descriptions for each song individually and see if there's a way to make the music player play through the whole album (just plays one song and stops atm). That and I need to figure out the best way to approach direct downloads, but for now other sites where you can find them are up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://putz.space/music/"&gt;Go check it out!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="music"></category></entry><entry><title>Updates</title><link href="https://putz.space/2019/03/18/2019-03-18-updates/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-18T01:22:03-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-18T01:22:03-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-03-18:/2019/03/18/2019-03-18-updates/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Been working on the stylesheet all night and I think it's in a place where the experience should hopefully be a little better finally, especially for mobile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically the only thing I have to do now is set up a system for making posts (or just learning Markdown and type …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Been working on the stylesheet all night and I think it's in a place where the experience should hopefully be a little better finally, especially for mobile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically the only thing I have to do now is set up a system for making posts (or just learning Markdown and type it up in a text editor I guess like a nerd lol), figure out how I want to host my music and I think from there most of the setup should be done. Anyway, hopefully this will be the start a of a long fruitful journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll see if it's worth it to do blogging or not. You can catch me on other social media found either in the &lt;a href="../pages/about.html"&gt;about&lt;/a&gt; page or in the footer for the real shitposts though lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS, just discovered &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sCNlt5nvSI8"&gt;FKJ&lt;/a&gt;. Go check him out he's good shit!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>Website launch</title><link href="https://putz.space/2019/03/12/website-launch/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-03-12:/2019/03/12/website-launch/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well hello there! I'm starting a website because I want to have a place where 
people can stay in touch with me and see what I'm up to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just recently switched to pelican to run things because it offers more
powerful tools for running a blog than &lt;a href="http://zim-wiki.org"&gt;zim-wiki&lt;/a&gt;, which …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well hello there! I'm starting a website because I want to have a place where 
people can stay in touch with me and see what I'm up to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just recently switched to pelican to run things because it offers more
powerful tools for running a blog than &lt;a href="http://zim-wiki.org"&gt;zim-wiki&lt;/a&gt;, which I use for taking notes
and keeping track of other stuff in my life. It can technically also publish
websites, but it's kinda limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is the first blog post, testing that out! I'll be adding more as I go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working on the CSS so it looks a little better and stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category></entry></feed>