<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>putz.space - self-help</title><link href="https://putz.space/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://putz.space/feeds/self-help.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://putz.space/</id><updated>2019-08-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Love, dating and relationships</title><link href="https://putz.space/blog/two-years-together/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-08-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-08-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-08-09:/blog/two-years-together/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently my partner and I celebrated our two year anniversary. I thought it would be a good time to reflect on my experiences not only dating, but now also maintaining a relationship. It may not be my first, but it's been a pretty awesome journey. I hope this will be useful to those interested in talking about and learning more on both, but mostly I just know younger me would have appreciated these notes lol. Long but good, enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.deviantart.com/afiya-numbuhnine/art/Mr-Pig-and-Tree-Trunks-Hug-318424108" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="https://putz.space/blog/covers/tree-trunks-and-pig.png" alt="Tree Trunks &amp; Mr. Pig from Adventure Time"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="two-years"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Two years together&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently it was a special day, because it's been two years since I met the love of my life. She's pretty special and I feel quite lucky to have found her. Sadly you, the Internet, probably won't meet her unless you know me personally, which is unfortunate cause she's great. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully though, you'll still find this reflection useful anyway, because I'd like to talk more about my experiences dating in general as well as how we've maintained our relationship up until now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; I'm not an expert. These are just my reflections. Your mileage may vary, especially if you're a person of color, queer or someone that isn't a straight white male. If you're lacking stability in your life, it can be harder to hold any kind of relationship at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, I offer you my ramblings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div id="toc"&gt;
&lt;p id="toc-header"&gt;Contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#two-years"&gt;Two years together&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#dating"&gt;Dating&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#bumpy-road"&gt;A long and bumpy road&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#pick-up"&gt;My pick-up phase&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#talking"&gt;Actually talking to people&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#making-moves"&gt;Making moves&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#relationships"&gt;Relationships&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#girlfriend"&gt;My first girlfriend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#breakup"&gt;My first breakup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#the-one"&gt;Finding the right one&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#tips"&gt;TIPs on Trust, Intimacy and Passion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#trust"&gt;Trust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#intimacy"&gt;Intimacy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#passion"&gt;Passion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#solved"&gt;Relationships: Solved!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="dating"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Dating&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr style="border: 1px solid #AAA;"/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a name="bumpy-road"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A long and bumpy road&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
I didn't start out confident about who I am. I slowly discovered who I was as I became an adult. These days I'm kinda glad that I was too nerdy and awkward in high school to date anyway. It saved a lot of drama and heartache during some crucial developmental years, but at the time I was worried about finding someone and you know, doin' it or whatever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="pick-up"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My pick-up phase&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
I've always been independent and curious to learn, so one day in high school I decided to read more about dating online. When I came across the pick-up community on Reddit I spent a lot of time reading advice and other stuff. To be clear, it's a bit weird. There's some hit-or-miss advice and some questionable views on women. The ideology around pick-up can get toxic if you're not careful to read between the lines, but the advice offers a concrete view of the process to someone who is absolutely clueless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a few gems that stuck with me to this day. In fact, the best advice you could even apply to other types relationships and stuff in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advice like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leave someone better than you found them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take care of your physical health.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dress in clothes that fit. In my case I altered them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't be afraid to make advances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rejection is good because you waste less time wondering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how to build rapport.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-improvement is sexy: Go to the gym, pick up a hobby, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do things that make you happy and own it (as in, don't be ashamed).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's probably more, but this is what stuck with me as some of the healthier gems of the pick-up community. Some of the toxic things to avoid can be basically be summed up with: &lt;strong&gt;avoid any advice that emphasizes quantity over quality.&lt;/strong&gt; When you start to focus on more hook-ups over enjoying yourself with someone then you start to walk down a path which overemphasizes sex as a goal instead one of many ways to build a meaningful connection with someone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't get me wrong, sex is fun (important to remember that sometimes it's not though), but when you start to care too much about it then the desperation reeks from miles away. That impacts your ability to have fun too which creates a dangerous spiral of Bad Vibes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can imagine, at first I spent a lot more time reading than I actually did talking to women. I did try to apply what I was learning online in the real world, but quite frankly I was just too damn shy and nervous most of the time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also had unrealistic expectations. I would overthink situations as simple as walking by a cute woman on my way to class in college. I would kick myself for not immediately stopping in the middle of the sidewalk (bustling with people) to tell them they're cute and ask them out. The reality is though that most people don't want to be hassled when they're on their way to something that's time sensitive like classes, so I probably saved myself some embarassment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's not to say asking out someone you've never met (called a "cold approach" in the lingo) can't work, and you should definitely get out of your comfort zone at some point (in a way that respects people's rejection if it happens), but I placed some heavy pressure on myself because dudes online made it look so easy by editing together footage of the times they were actually succesful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of my obsession came from the fact that I just really wanted to know what it was like to be in a relationship and have sex, because it's glorified to no end. I mean for good reason, being in love with someone is great. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it's also important to understand that some relationships are horrible messes that you'd be much happier not having. Like really, really fucking bad. Luckily I've never had a truly toxic relationship, but I'm sure people out there will tell you that love doesn't exist because they went through some fucked up shit that ruined them forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="talking"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Actually talking to people&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
What helped me more than any advice a man could write up about seducing women was just becoming friends with women. In my attempts at talking to women I was interested in I made a few friends who I never did anything romantic with because they weren't interested in me or they weren't in a good spot to have a relationship. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I got to know them I found they were cool people. In fact, I found out I just plain like women in general and hanging out with them. They're like, actual people who have personalities and stuff, it's weird I know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I will say that it's important to mention your interest in someone from the get go instead of letting things build up and expecting it to "just happen", because if you don't then it becomes awkward the longer your let your feelings grow unmentioned. Remember, being rejected isn't a bad thing and who knows, maybe they feel the same way! Make a move, see where things go. Being friends can be fine too, just don't expect they'll change their minds if they said they're not interested at all. I've learned that the hard way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were very few times where I did anything that could be considered a cold approach, and even fewer that were successful. Not to say that it can't be, but you really have to build your social-emotional skills to read people and your ability have meaningful conversations with strangers which will likely come with a lot of painful failures before you get there. In fact, it's a good life skill to build for meeting people in general, but it takes work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, far and away the easiest times I had in hitting it off with people were in social settings with friends of friends or at a party. It eases a lot of the tension when you're in a safe place having fun with people you already trust. Parties are a great place to meet people, but you can also just meet people through hobbies, at a café, or out and about with friends. Don't ask people out in a dark alley or the cashier at the grocery store! It's weird and will make someone feel threatened if they reject you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't mean to say that I don't get nervous talking to people either, cause I still do, but it's easier to get over it now. Because the single thing getting in the way of actually doing it, is just doing it. It really depends on how I feel mentally though and my interest in actually socializing. In the end it's something that takes practice like any other skill though. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people are clueless when it comes to relationships and meeting people, so you shouldn't feel bad if you also are. Be honest about it and the other person will appreciate that more than painful attempts at powering through a macho facade. If they don't, fuck 'em (well, not literally).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="making-moves"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Making moves&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
One of the areas I struggled with the most when initially starting out was how to make a move. What the hell does that even mean, you know?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, it's not as straight forward as it seems. Making a move can look different depending which stage of getting to know someone you're at. Saying "Hi" is a great first move, but whatever you do don't use a pick-up line. It's about as interesting as saying "SO HOW BOUT THAT WEATHER!?". Well, unless you have some damn good delivery, but if that's the case you don't need my help anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone has their own style too. I would often say hi, compliment/comment on the thing about them that drew me to them in the first place (a nice shirt, their hair, or maybe they've got a cool button on their backpack). From there I would try to ask a question that would tell me more about them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My go to get-to-know-you question in a lot of social situations these days (beyond dating even) is "What's the coolest thing I should know about you?", because it does a few things. First, it tells you if they're actually interested in talking to you, because if they're not they'll just say "uhhhh I don't know", which even if they ARE interested in talking to you is already a bad sign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, it gives you an idea of what they're into and starts a conversation that's actually interesting instead of what job they sell their lives away at or some other mundane bullshit that nobody cares about but everyone asks because we're so deprived of excitement in our lives that sometimes don't remember what fun is... &lt;em&gt;Ahem&lt;/em&gt;, anyway. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key isn't that it has to actually be something cool, it's just an open-ended question that can lead to a genuine conversation. Come up with a question about something that interests you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you're making moves the key is to figure out:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who they are.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How receptive they are.&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;If they're worth your time.&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You make yourself vulnerable by putting yourself out there and facing the potential for rejection at the hands of the other person. How they respond to that tells you if they're a person worth talking to, or equally as important, if you need to readjust your style and approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always respect rejection! It doesn't mean you can't try again later, because sometimes people just need to get to know you better before they're willing to open up in that way. The same goes for advancing into sexually charged territory. A friendly touch on the arm after you've established a base level of trust, telling them you think they're cute or asking them what they'd do if you kiss them are all ways to call the question of "are you into me?" and escalate things. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never force yourself onto someone though. Yes, confidence and assertiveness can be sexy, but so is respect and consent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are whole books written on the details of making moves, but really you should develop your own style that flows with who you are. You're not a caveman trying to hunt a gazelle though, you're trying to get to know someone enough to have a good time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the timeline on these things, there really isn't one. You can go from "Hi!" to sex in a day (or less) or it can drag out over a few weeks or a couple months (likely not much longer though before they start to wonder if you're even interested). It really depends on how trustworthy you come off and the person's past experience with relationships. Some people have been hurt before so they may be reluctant to open up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suffice to say it, eventually I figured dating out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="relationships"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Relationships&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr style="border: 1px solid #AAA;"/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a name="girlfriend"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My first girlfriend&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
I finally met someone who wanted to keep seeing me more than once! I had technically dated people prior, but not successfully. We met through mutual friends, but didn't hang out right away. However, I eventually came back a semester later after winter break with freshly altered clothes, my hair held together with cream so I didn't look like a middle schooler and new found confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things didn't start from 0 to 100 in one swoop, instead it was gradual. We both were interested in other people more than each other initially, but as we got to know each other we found out that we really liked each other. Eventually we started hanging out more, going on adventures and decided to do the whole boyfriend/girlfriend thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was nice to finally be with someone because I could stop worrying about dating. I learned more about what I was actually looking for in a partner, which helps you avoid falling into the trap of just being in a relationship to avoid being alone. Being alone is ok, or at least it's better than being with someone shitty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But things didn't last forever, which is common for college relationships anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="breakup"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My first breakup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
When I came home from a long car ride only to get dumped in a truck outside the dorms, it definitely wasn't a great feeling. But the most important thing she told me was more or less "It might not seem like it now, but things will be better eventually". It didn't feel great, but it never does for either side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually things did get better though and we were better off individually for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help ease the pain I hung out with friends. It was super important to be with people who I could just exist around. It was part of the healing process as I felt and dealt with my feelings. It was good to lift my spirits. Not all breakups are made the same of course, but if it's unwanted then it's rough. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobbies helped me maintain composure too. Music is always one way I've gotten through stuff, this was no exception. Getting outside helped a lot too. I spent some moody evenings in the marsh by the cemetary, I'll admit it! Finding solitude when you live at the dorms is hard, so being outside helped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later I learned that sometimes it's better to break up than to carry on with a relationship that just won't work though. Sometimes there's just a fundamental difference, changed feelings or some reason breaking up makes more sense. Sometimes it's mutual. You should try to communicate if you want to save the relationship, because talking it out can help, but you're not obligated to either. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not really easy no matter which way you shake it, but it can be healthier to acknowledge it won't work if you reach your tipping point and decide it's been enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="the-one"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Finding the right one&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Since then I dated around and found who I'm with now. It's been better than I could have hoped. A lot of luck was involved in meeting each other, but staying together has been a commitment that requires work. Not an excessive amount, but sometimes it requires thought and effort. For me past experiences helped so I was aware of the pitfalls and problems that can come up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realize to some people that two years is nothing, but to me it's the longest relationship I've had, so that's what I'm working with lol. I foresee many more :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We met online through OKCupid, which filtered out a lot of fundamental questions that can take a while to come up in a relationship the old-fashioned way. So out the gate we were pretty well matched. It was nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some things can't be worked on. But for those that can, I've identified a few important areas that at least merit mention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="tips"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;TIPs on Trust, Intimacy and Passion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
There's a lot of cliché remarks about the importance of communication and commitment when it comes to dating, but that's because it's true. They're an important tool to help maintain these three areas of a relationship, otherwise they can start to degrade over time. When trust is lost, it closes off intimacy which will start to eat into the passion that brought you together in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone has different ways of expressing their needs. Some are quieter because they've been socialized not to complain and others will let you know when you're fuckin' up no problem. Sometimes we aren't even in tune with the ways we're reacting to a situation ourselves until it's been going on for a while. Espcially if you don't reflect much and find your life is a blur that you can barely keep track of. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of how you do though, it's important to be able to express yourself in a healthy way with a partner who is willing to listen. Inevitably, something will happen that you or they didn't mean to fuck up your trust of each other, whether it's hurt feelings, a misunderstanding or you-name-it. At some point, we just fuck up because we're human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="trust"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Trust&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Trust is when you're willing to to make yourself vulnerable to someone in some capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means you expect that what they say is true, they'll follow through on commitments and you can depend on them in general. If you don't have that, then it's not a healthy relationship. That isn't to say you should blindly trust people, because it should be earned. But if it's not there then that's bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When that trust is broken so is the special connection that makes the relationship work. Even in friendships trust is important. Without trust, waiting for a text message can lead to paranoia that your partner is cheating. With it, you know that whatever they're doing is fine and you'll see them again at some point anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many things can eat away at trust, so it's important to identify the root cause of the problem which requires communication and commitment to a solution that takes dealing with difficult emotions sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="intimacy"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Intimacy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Intimacy is a space opened up through trust. It's when you share your existence together as you are without bullshit in between and accept each other openly. It's brushing your teeth together, eating dinner, watching movies, goofin' around, playing games and sharing your personal stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can't repair trust, you can't repair intimacy. Sometimes it's them, sometimes it's you, and sometimes it's a situation that can be worked on. But without the ability to trust one another, opening yourself up is hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intimacy provides the spark that reminds you why the person you're with is special. It gives you a connection that only you and the other person share which seperates them from just any ol' body. The special appreciation that intimacy gives you for someone is what fuels passion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="passion"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Passion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Maintaining a relationship isn't just about fixing fuck ups. It's also about excitement and fun. Passion comes from being with someone who makes you feel great. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, that can be as sexual as it sounds (it's an important question for compatibility at least), but it goes beyond it too. Making someone feel appreciated, having a great time goofing around, playing video games, going out to dinner, showering in the morning, doing new things and just living life in general with each other in a way that makes you feel glad to know the other person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passion comes from genuinely liking the person you're with and expressing it in the space opened up by intimacy and trust. Finding time to keep it alive is hard. Sometimes it means doing things you might not always like.  Cleaning around the house, taking care of yourself and otherwise just being an Adult Human Being are important ways to maintain the fabric of a healthy relationship and the environment it lives in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because if your partner has to take care of two people all by themselves, they're gonna burn out quick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="solved"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Dating and Relationships: Solved!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
So this post turned out to be waaaaaaaay longer than I had anticipated and there's still things I feel like I haven't covered yet. If you've stuck around, then hopefully you found this useful. This is just my own experience. Dating and relationships are complicated subjects that a lot of people are interested in. It was something that came up in my poll of interests y'all had!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal was to offer some insights that I feel are healthy and generalizable for those curious. I know that if I was younger I would have found these thoughts useful to myself trying to navigate what it means to date, have relationships and all that stuff. For young men growing up, there's a bunch of semi-decent advice wrapped up in unhealthy views of sex and women that focuses on the result and not the process or even meaningful connection. I'm sure the same is true for women and folks who live beyond the binary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of that advice though is worth expanding on and using to understand our desire for intimacy, connection, purpose and support so that we can grow with the love of others. Even if you don't want to fall in love and do just want to have a lot of sex, then go for it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because at the end of the day, our relationships should make us better people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until next time,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Putz&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="dating"></category><category term="self-help"></category></entry><entry><title>Ways to replace Facebook</title><link href="https://putz.space/blog/ways-to-replace-facebook/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-06-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-06-26:/blog/ways-to-replace-facebook/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A friend on my feed recently shared a story about a day in the life of a Facebook moderator, which unsurprisingly isn't a great time. After reading it they were asking themself if they could genuinely leave Facebook. That inspired me to ask the question on my feed "What keeps you on Facebook?", hoping that I could write about my experience leaving and what I did to replace the things that kept me there. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Facebook logo" src="https://putz.space/blog/covers/ways-to-replace-facebook.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href="https://fanpagecash.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/leaving-facebook.png"&gt;https://fanpagecash.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/leaving-facebook.png&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend on my feed recently shared &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/19/18681845/facebook-moderator-interviews-video-trauma-ptsd-cognizant-tampa" target="_blank"&gt;a story about a day in the life of a Facebook moderator&lt;/a&gt;, which unsurprisingly isn't a great time. After reading it they were asking themself if they could genuinely leave Facebook. That inspired me to ask the question on my feed "What keeps you on Facebook?", hoping that I could write about my experience leaving and what I did to replace the things that kept me there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I may be back for now, I think I found some solutions that could help people for a few problems I was having when I finally decided to leave it. Hopefully this can serve as inspiration to you in your pursuit to finally hop off of Facebook, but if not you can at least implement one or two of these things and slowly add more over time so that when you feel confident enough to hit the permanent delete button, you'll be ready. Most of this can peacefully co-exist with Facebook too honestly anyway, so maybe it'll be useful even if you never leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could go on a long philosophical rant about why you should leave, from the privacy invasions characteristic of a dystopian novel to the huge amounts of mental energy it can suck away from you, but I'm sure if you're reading this you already have your own reasons for being interested in leaving or entertaining the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sad reality is that in some ways Facebook may be the best place for certain stuff depending on what your goals are or what you're looking for. However, you'd be surprised just how easy it really is to get by without Facebook. Admittedly, I'm back on it though, but &lt;a href="https://putz.space/blog/returning-to-facebook/"&gt;I wrote about why at length already&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've ordered this list based on what I've found most important personally. It reflects my own needs, so for some of the missing pieces you may have to do your own digging still. I did conduct a Facebook poll to try and see what people use theirs for to get an idea of what people might want to read about. So while I could go on about all of Facebook's features, I've decided to stick to my own experience and what people cared to hear about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it's a long one...
&lt;div id="toc"&gt;
&lt;p id="toc-header"&gt;Contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#feed"&gt;News feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#socialmedia"&gt;Social media&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#music"&gt;Music &amp;amp; sharing projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#photos"&gt;Photos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#messaging"&gt;Messaging and friends list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#events"&gt;Events&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#chronicle"&gt;Chronicle of life events&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="feed"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;News feed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly a pretty big one in my limited survey. Facebook's algorithm makes following news sources highly unpredictable which is super annoying if you want the latest updates from sources you trust. So instead of dealing with that bullshit, you can use &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS" target="_blank"&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt;. Click the link if you want the scoop on it, but I'm just focusing on how to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing you need to find is an RSS reader. Think of it as a personal electronic mailbox that's on your digital doorfront. So what you need are addresses that stuff your mail box with chronologically sorted, no-bullshit news straight from your favorite publications as they push them out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding an RSS feed on a website can sometimes be complicated. In fact, it's not garaunteed you'll even find one, but usually it's accompanied by this cute logo: &lt;a href="http://putz.space/feeds/all.rss.xml"&gt;&lt;img src="https://putz.space/images/articles/rss.png" alt="RSS" width="16px" height="16px" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is that some RSS readers will just find the feed if you enter in the website's address though, so you might not even have to think about it too hard depending on what you go with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use RSS to follow podcasts, YouTube channels, blogs, you name it. In fact, you can use it to follow my own blog! I try to make it simple, so you can &lt;a href="http://putz.space/feeds/all.atom.xml" target="_blank"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt; or the logo above to copy the address to add me. It's just that sometimes other websites don't advertise this functionality for whatever reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have trouble finding an RSS feed, try googling it. A simple "[website] rss feed" will suffice usually, but in one case I was trying to follow the local news and I was getting stumped on finding any RSS functionality. However, I googled the name of the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Content_management_system" target="_blank"&gt;CMS (Content Management System)&lt;/a&gt; that I found at the bottom of the page and added "rss" to the search and it took me to the documentation for the software they use. Turns out, all I had to do was add &amp;amp;f=rss at the end of the URL after using their website's search function and it worked! Usually it's easier than that though. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Practice on my own blog if you'd like by adding it into a feed reader of your choice. Some web browsers even have readers of their own built in. There's a variety of readers to choose from, some only working locally on the computer they're installed on and others being online subscription services you can use that will be stored in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If RSS is too complicated for your tastes, there are other ways to get your news from Google to Apple to Reddit, but this puts more control over who you get to see in your own hands without algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refer to these links for more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison_of_feed_aggregators#Operating_system_support" target="_blank"&gt;Wikipedia - List of Feed Aggregators by OS they're available on&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://fossbytes.com/best-rss-reader-apps/" target="_blank"&gt;Fossbytes - Best RSS reader apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lifewire.com/top-free-online-rss-readers-3486649" target="_blank"&gt;Lifewire - Best online RSS readers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="socialmedia"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Social media&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping up with friends and family, besides following the news, was hands down the biggest reason people are still on Facebook. Which makes sense, because that's the reason I'm back. Honestly, I haven't really found an alternative that I would claim allows you to stay in touch with friends as well as I'd like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, there are alternatives like Reddit, Snapchat and Instagram, but Instagram is owned by Facebook anyway so it's like a different room of the same house. I do find it less addictive though so maybe that or Snapchat could be a way to stay in touch if you find Facebook problematic for whatever reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did dive into an alternative up-and-coming social media platform called &lt;a href="https://fediverse.party/en/fediverse/" target="_blank"&gt;"The Fediverse"&lt;/a&gt;. The technology has some great potential to reshape the social media landscape in the face of increasing concerns over Facebook's monopoly of our online social lives. The way it works is it lets a bunch of different platforms communicate with each other through a standarized protocol. It'd be like if Facebook and Twitter would let you subscribe to users from either platform, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The low barrier to entry gives communities an easy way to create their own online space so that they can have more control over them without corporate influence. It's devoid of any advertisements, bullshit feed algorithms that prey on your pscyhe, and has a somewhat healthier community (parts of it anyhow) that actually wants to invite people to be themselves without all the hate you find elsewhere. It's not perfect, but it's neat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally use &lt;a href="http://joinmastodon.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; with the handle &lt;a href="https://mastodon.technology/@nergalur" target="_blank"&gt;@nurgalur@mastodon.technology&lt;/a&gt; (at the time of writing anyway, see the about/contact page for the latest if this link is broken), but if you dig around there are other ways to set up your own account. Pretty much only lefty nerds interested in tech and queer people of color are on there right now, so it might be a niche only interesting to myself and a select few Facebook friends for the time being. The memes are pretty funny too, but it takes a while to get the in-jokes. Anyway, probably not for everyone, but that's been my journey into the realm of alternative social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="music"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Music &amp;amp; sharing projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly I wasn't the only one who wanted to find a way to share my music, and by extension personal projects, with friends. It's one of the reasons I've returned to Facebook before. I would previously share SoundCloud links on my feed for friends to keep up with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But honestly, SoundCloud is pretty damn awful. At least sound quality wise, although the interface is decent enough. Listening to any of the higher frequencies in a song though makes it apparent that SoundCloud is clearly not making enough money or something because that shit is compressed as hell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I actually ended up making this website with my own &lt;a href="https://putz.space/music/" target="_blank"&gt;music&lt;/a&gt; section to fix that problem. By using GitHub pages I have free hosting for &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Static_web_page" target="_blank"&gt;static web pages&lt;/a&gt;, all I had to buy was the domain name for the website (~$3-11/yr depending) and use &lt;a href="https://blog.getpelican.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; to generate the website with. There's technically a limit to how much you can upload, but 1GB is a lot of space for a blog before you start having problems with storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still link to other places you can find my music like Bandcamp and SoundCloud depending on where I've uploaded it to, but this way people can at least come to me to find the best quality version of my work, even if they prefer to listen to it elsewhere. You can also share all your music with something like &lt;a href="http://distrokid.com" target="_blank"&gt;DistroKid&lt;/a&gt; which will distribute it for like $20/yr, whether or not you have a website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the actual "publicity" side of things, that's beyond the scope of this article and I'm not really the one you should consult on "getting big", but by having my own web page people will at least always know where they can find me, whether I'm on Facebook or not. I also intend to use this space for any other projects I get involved in, but music has been my biggest so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="photos"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Photos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social media has created a convenient way for people to keep track of all of their photos, and Facebook is quite useful. However, "you never really know what you've got until it's gone" as the saying goes, and it's particularly true when the Internet is down and you can't access your shit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's why I use an external hard drive to back up all my important photos. Really there's no reason not to use an online service like what's offered by Google, Apple, Facebook or Instagram as well as having your photos backed up locally, but I personally don't find myself sharing my photos that often anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set up my own local over-the-network backup solution that automatically transfers my photos from my phone to my computer, which I'd like to write about more at some point in the future (definitely beyond the scope of this article), but even just following the routine of backing up any photos from your phone/camera to a hard drive every month is a simple way to make sure you don't lose everything if your phone dies. It's also nice for any photos you wouldn't want to lose in a security leak or by having your account suspended by surprise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S: If you have photos on Facebook you want to download there's a way to actually download your entire photo collection, just search "download facebook photo backup".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as sharing photos though, I haven't really looked around a whole lot because honestly it doesn't matter as much to me and I feel weird about putting my photos online a lot of times anyway. But if it does matter to you, you'll have to do your own digging and let me know what you find because as far as I'm aware, Instagram, Snapchat and Facebook are the best in town for that one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="messaging"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Messaging and friends list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one was pretty important to me, but super easy to replace. You can literally think of anything you use that isn't Facebook and you're already there. I use Signal, Telegram, SMS, Email, Instagram (although technically also owned by Facebook), Whatsapp (same boat as Instagram), sometimes I check my Snapchat, but honestly you probably don't need my help to find a technical solution here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use Facebook to get all of your friends contact info and put it into whatever you use to save your contacts. If you have a phone you probably already have some cloud-based way of doing this. If you want to hop off the cloud though, you can opt to save contacts locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my experience, I found it was very challenging to find the time in the day to keep up with nearly the same number of people though as I did through Facebook. The solution here is partly kinda beyond just finding the right technology unfortunately, which is a whole 'nother topic on its own. However, you might find that you just don't need to keep up with everyone you've met either, which is totally cool too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="events"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Events&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, it's not impossible to find events without Facebook! &lt;a href="http://meetup.com" target="_blank"&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; is very useful for finding events locally. Now actually going to them is another story. Something also true of Facebook when the real issue is finding the time to do anything ever lol, but it's a good alternative if you want to look around at what's going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For birthdays, some calendar apps even let you set friends' birthdays in your calendar from the contact info if you want to keep track of that. Could be another thing you add to your list of details to get from friends before you hop off Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other ways to find events include just looking at the local paper, or asking what your friends are up to and they'll probably let you know. Or if you go to a café or bar, sometimes they have a bulletin board. If there's a TV show you like or band they likely have a website you can visit with touring dates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granted, all of that is predicated on living in a city where people do things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="chronicle"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chronicle of life events&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People didn't mention this as a thing they particularly care about, however I notice some people use Facebook to post memories of way back from years ago. I honestly don't keep track of many of my personal milestones on Facebook, so it's not that useful to me for that. What I have found helpful for remembering those sorts of things is keeping a daily log which I wrote about extensively already, so if this is a reason you find yourself using Facebook, consider reading what &lt;a href="https://putz.space/blog/keep-it-together/"&gt;I wrote on that here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="conclusion"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully some of this has been helpful to you, or at the very least interesting. Some of these things are just good ideas, even if you don't plan on leaving, because they allow you to take back some of the control you've potentially given up over your digital life by letting Facebook take care of it. Even if you already deleted it, you can still do some of these things to replace the useful bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as I've said before you might not be able to replace everything to the same degree. Some of the things I didn't even touch on in this post such as groups, the marketplace, job postings, etc, either have more popular alternatives you can search for if you want or I just didn't use them enough to care. For example, I've gotten most job postings through Indeed or found used stuff on Craigslist. Some of the things you may have to decide to live without if you ever do finally decide to leave Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless, this has been a summary of my journey in finding ways to replace a few of the useful bits of Facebook through my numerous times leaving.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="tech"></category><category term="self-help"></category></entry><entry><title>How I keep it together</title><link href="https://putz.space/blog/keep-it-together/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-06-01T15:15:32-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-01T15:15:32-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-06-01:/blog/keep-it-together/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A while back in college I decided to start keeping a daily log and to-do list. That sparked a few routines that I started to use to keep my life together. I figured some people might find it helpful if I reflected on that journey and how I started adulting. So yeah, enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The titanic sinking in an infomercial" src="https://putz.space/blog/covers/keep-it-together.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided I want to openly reflect on how I organize my day to day because I think it could be helpful for people who are asking themselves how to do that. It's not a question I intentionally set out to answer when I started the routines that I use to keep track of my life and accomplish goals. However, these practices have lead me down a path that keep me focused and self aware so that I'm in tune with myself, my needs and where I'm going in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how did I get there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The daily log&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Zim wiki daily log" src="https://putz.space/images/diy/daily-log.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started keeping a daily log on December 17th, 2014. I originally started it because I was in college and I was bored at home over the winter. I was curious about learning the &lt;a href="http://python.org" target="_blank"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; programming language and I thought a good project would be to create my own note-taking software to help me in school. Then I quickly realized it would be a lot of work and decided instead to just find an open source project that someone already started (also written in Python) that would let me take notes more effectively than a bunch of scattered word docs all over My Documents like the rest of people in class. Fun fact, I still have those notes laying around too, even if I hardly reference them. At the time though, I found the software you see in the screenshot to be very useful for school too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting the habit of remembering to log my day was difficult, but not impossible the more I stuck with it. I was also inspired by a Life Pro-Tip I heard a while back on Reddit about keeping notes of all the happy moments in a year, putting them in a jar and opening the jar one New Years to remember the year. So instead of just the happy memories I decided to log the mundane and bad ones too. It's kinda fun to reflect back on and helps avoid the memory rot our brains are prone to when it comes to remembering certain details. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there I also had another idea...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;My to-do list&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Zim wiki to-do list" src="https://putz.space/images/diy/todo-list.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being on my own in college meant I had a new level of independence to be free with, but also live up to. In order to keep things straight I started to keep a to-do list, which I figured would go very well with the daily log. The nice thing about that combination is that you can set your goals and confirm with yourself whether you did them or not by simply reading the log. Over the years I've learned how to combine the two to recalibrate my life if I start to notice that I'm not getting done what I need to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this an unrealistic goal? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do I just need to define it better so it's more clear what to do? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the hell did I last get a hair cut again? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions like these and more are easier to answer if you have a running log of your life to double check if you're not even able to keep track of what you ate last for breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of these habits helped build into each other so I could maintain a routine that I wouldn't just simply stop doing one day from forgetting to do it. I also made sure that they were both simple enough to keep me doing them. The daily log is a mostly logistical thing for me, but I occassionally engage in more emotionally detailed reflections that I save in LibreOffice docs to go back to once and a while if I want, because that can be helpful for yourself too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main thing though, is organizing what you need to do in your life so that you don't forget to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, that's not accidentally capitalized while the others aren't. &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Getting_Things_Done" target="_blank"&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/a&gt; is an actual method some weird business lookin' boy from the year 2001 wrote for getting shit done. The software I use, &lt;a href="http://zim-wiki.org" target="_blank"&gt;Zim wiki&lt;/a&gt; includes an abridged explanation of how to integrate it into your workflow through the software, but anyway I'm gonna give you an even simpler run-down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, at some point I realized that my previous methods of keeping track of my to-do list were insufficient so I decided to investigate some more. The way I've adapted Getting Things Done is pretty simple. You don't even need to use the software I do to really implement this into your life, or any of these tips for that matter. You can work it into your life how makes the most sense to you. Creativity is the spice of life and all that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The flow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing you do is identify a task. Can it be done in less than 5 minutes? Then do it! Seriously, stuff like hanging up your clothes, putting a new toilet paper roll on the holder or loading and unloading a dishwasher are stuff that will vastly improve your quality of life without building up into a huge 30 minute mess down the line. So you'll be much better off for just doing them if you have the time. Sometimes we don't though, which is when you go to the next step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;INBOX and to-do list&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Zim wiki Inbox" src="https://putz.space/images/diy/todo-inbox.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write it down in my INBOX (as seen above) and if I can't think about it at the time then I just come back to it later. When I can take the time to process it (which I have a little reminder to do located at the top of the page so it shows up in Zim wiki's to-do list feature), I'll decide if it's something I genuinely want to put time into or discard. If it's a big project, I'll start to give it it's own space on a page of it's own under the Projects folder, otherwise you can just throw it on your everyday to-do or chores list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A chores list is something I look at frequently to remind myself what tasks I have to keep up with routinely (weekly, monthly, etc). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My to-do list is full of single, line item things that I need to take care of that might be related by subject matter but are independent stuff to do one time, probably at a certain date. Maybe I just have to pay a particular bill instead of one that is recurring for example or I should remember to call up a friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Projects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Zim wiki Project list: Automotive" src="https://putz.space/images/diy/todo-automotive.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Projects folder is where I take what is turning into a huge section of it's own list of related tasks all about one subject or on-going project in my life in the to-do list. My Automotive to-do list for example includes the entire maintenance schedule for my car, problems and repairs as they come up and anything related to my car, because that's how much is going on with it. That way I can make sure I'm up to date on the thing it needs taken care of routinely while keeping track of the small things that come up along the way like any rust spots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Someday&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last thing on the side panel you may see is the "SomeDay" folder. It's a place where I put anything I think of that isn't a task that's been formulated in concrete terms of when, what or how to do it. Maybe I would like to learn a thing, write an article or process an idea I'm having in a way more in-depth than my inbox. Or maybe something from the inbox is growing into a larger idea. I honestly haven't found myself using it that much, but it's a recommendation from the Getting Things Done method and I've been using it to just keep track of whims and dreams I have that I don't quite want to give up on yet but don't have any idea about what to do logistically for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you've made it this far you're clearly interested in trying to get your life together. I have found the above practices extremely fruitful when it comes to keeping it together for myself. Like I said, this turned out to be the product of what was more or less an accident and me wanting to nerd out on taking notes about myself because I was in college at the time and found those skills highly useful to transfer into my daily life. Unlike everyone else who went to college and "didn't learn anything useful", I found the mindset of being a self-directed studious individual has allowed me to optimize the way I spend my time so less of it is spent on shit that I've let get way out of control. Instead of letting my mind get scared of being bored and instantly type in facebook.com into my web browser, I try to direct my energies into this, certian times more successfully than others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see the memes of people who don't like to plan their life because they want it to be spontaneous or whatever, but actually having my shit all laid out in an easy to keep track of way has allowed me to have the ability to use my free time in the ways I truly want to, instead of dealing with unexpected consequences from letting one area of my life go to shit. It's not to say I don't run into ruts, roadblocks or stressful situations. These routines just allow me to deal with them more effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's certainly an element of luck and privilege as with anything in life as to why I've been able to keep my shit together. But I also found these skills useful and fundamental to my life as an adult so that I can be self-aware and on top of my shit. So take it for what you will, but I hope you may find my reflections useful. If you haven't, well my blog helps me process my life too so in the end it's all good anyway lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anything you can at least see where I got the inspiration from for my website's CSS style.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diy"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="self-help"></category><category term="personal"></category></entry></feed>