<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>putz.space - social</title><link href="https://putz.space/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://putz.space/feeds/social.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://putz.space/</id><updated>2020-03-27T20:28:10-05:00</updated><entry><title>Hello Neighbors!</title><link href="https://putz.space/blog/hello-neighbors/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-03-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-03-27T20:28:10-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2020-03-27:/blog/hello-neighbors/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I flyered the block I live on because times are weird and we're going to need each other to get through whatever this crazy crisis is. Here's an explanation of why I did that and an introduction.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello neighbors!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you saw a flyer on your door and noticed the putz.space URL in the email that you saw, then you've found my blog!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long story short, times are weird. There's pandemic going on and society is shutting down. It's a bit scary to be honest. That means some people might need help financially. People might need help getting their groceries. Others might be willing to help people in their time of need with free food or a helping hand. Others yet maybe just want to get connected with their neighbors in these alienating times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you respond to my flyer I'll be connecting you to others in the community who also feel the need for that. I'll connect you to the email list and group chat where we can stay in touch. Feel free to join the facebook group for the whole neighborhood extending even beyond our block, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/whittiercares"&gt;Whittier &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/whittiercares"&gt;Cares.&lt;/a&gt; We're not the only block getting connected, others are as well across the metro!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's it really. I'm just trying to build the connections we'll need to take care of one another and get through this. If that sounds appealing to you then feel free to &lt;a href="mailto:neighbors@putz.space"&gt;contact me.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="blog"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="social"></category></entry><entry><title>Putz social post-mortem</title><link href="https://putz.space/blog/putz-social-post-mortem/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-11-22T13:22:53-06:00</published><updated>2019-11-22T13:22:53-06:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-11-22:/blog/putz-social-post-mortem/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Putz social is closed now. I tried a thing and it failed. Here's the post-mortem for it.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I opened up a Mastodon server for my friends to see if I could build a community of people I know on healthier social media. Obviously by reading the title you know that failed. Unsurprisingly, I am not the basis for a community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To those who were on, I thought it would be open longer so you could migrate your account elsewhere but canceling the automatic PayPal subscription seems to have killed the server right away. Sorry about that. Most people didn't have a whole lot to transfer anyway, but if you lost your follows list and actually cared about it, I'm sorry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a certain point I had to accept that it's not worth $210 a year to make posts on Mastodon by myself. There are bigger servers where I can sign-up for free. If you want to sign-up elsewhere you can find other servers at &lt;a href="http://joinmastodon.org"&gt;Join Mastodon.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Reddit yesterday I saw a comment about how as you grow up people just move on and a lot of the friends you had go elsewhere. While scrolling through my Mastodon feed of nobody who I knew in real life, it became painfully obvious it was true. Even in my daily life it's true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was holding on to the past, reaching out to a lot of people I'll never see again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought by opening up putz social and inviting people at the community level all at once to join that maybe it would have the inertia to grow. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slowly, I started to accept that this community building project was yet another failure as the days went on without anyone other than myself posting on the local timeline. Occassionally others would but not much, certainly not for months now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It finally clicked that it's time to move on yesterday in the afternoon, quite suddenly to be honest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you want to follow my new account I'm at &lt;a href="http://weirder.earth/@pootz"&gt;weirder.earth&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putz social is dead and now you know why. There are plenty of other servers though, so if you want a healthier social media environmemt that doesn't spy on you for advertisers, check out another server.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="blog"></category><category term="tech"></category><category term="social"></category></entry><entry><title>Making friends on Mastodon</title><link href="https://putz.space/blog/making-friends-mastodon/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-09T20:38:03-05:00</published><updated>2019-09-09T20:38:03-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-09-09:/blog/making-friends-mastodon/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Now that you've got an account on social.putz.space and know how to use Mastodon, the only thing left is finding people. More than just following people though, the Fediverse offers a cool space to meet people you wouldn't meet elsewhere. Let's learn how to make friends and follow people!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://putz.space/images/mastodon/mastodon-logo.png" alt="mastodon logo" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Ready to post but no one to listen...&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You've finally made an account on &lt;a href="https://social.putz.space"&gt;social.putz.space&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://putz.space/blog/intro-to-mastodon/"&gt;read my quick intro&lt;/a&gt;. The only thing left now is to make friends! Even if you don't necessarily want to make friends, this guide should help you find people to follow other than me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reached out to the Fediverse to ask people how they make friends. After reading what people had to say I've identified three key things you can do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Introduce yourself&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start by introducing yourself. You should use the &lt;strong&gt;#introductions&lt;/strong&gt; hashtag with a brief description of your interests (particularly the ones you'd like to post about). Use a # to tag words and make them searchable so that people can easily see what you're interested in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make it fun! This isn't work and it's not a dating app. Just be yoursef and own it. Odds are it'll fly right by on the Federated timeline anyway as a blip in the many toots of Mastodon history. No reason to be scared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus it's a great way to connect with people on the Local timeline. On mine it's probably people you already know, but even if you're on a different instance there are people eager to see who else is on the same server. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;in order to post to the timeline your posts have to be set to public.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://putz.space/images/mastodon/introductions.png" alt="me introducing myself on Mastodon" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Follow people&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Local or Federated timelines if you notice anyone who has interesting stuff to say, goofy shitposts or whatever draws your attention, check out their profile by clicking on their name. If you like their style then give 'em a follow! They might even follow you back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you follow someone active then you'll probably find more people to follow too, because you'll see who they're chatting with and boosting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can search by hashtag too. That way you can find posts lost to the sands of time without losing the people who post them. There's also a way to add featured hashtags to your account that will make it easier to find the stuff you're talking about on your public profile page for others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, you could always try the profile directory. It's optional though so not everyone is on it. If you want to be on it then enable the option in your profile preferences. To see the directory click on the menu button or just type the base url of the instance (social.putz.space in my case) and at /explore at the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://putz.space/images/mastodon/profile-directory-option.png" alt="profile directory option" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Be active&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it may seem awkward or make you nervous at first, you should just post! At least on putz social, you should feel like you're in a space where you can be genuine with who you are. You should post to your heart's content as long as that doesn't interfere with someone elses ability to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Mastodon doesn't have all the recommendations that Facebook or Twitter does for friends, memes, ideas, etc constantly in your face you have to actually post to be seen. Otherwise nobody will ever find you. Which is fine if that's what you want, but if you want to meet people then you've gotta post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interacting with people on the Fediverse is welcome. If you have a comment that will help someone's problem, brighten someone's day or if you've got something to say, then post it. Of course, favoriting and boosting are great ways to show appreciation and share good content with friends too. But only people who are following you can see your boosts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time the more you interact with people, hopefully the more they'll feel like friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need examples, here's one time when I complimented someone's avatar. Afterwards we started following each other!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://putz.space/images/mastodon/friends.png" alt="complimenting someone's avatar"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Comments&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post here if you've got comments or questions!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://social.putz.space/@pootz/102730959960835232/embed" class="mastodon-embed" style="max-width: 100%; border: 0" width="100%" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;script src="https://social.putz.space/embed.js" async="async"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</content><category term="blog"></category><category term="tech"></category><category term="social"></category><category term="mastodon"></category></entry><entry><title>Introduction to Mastodon</title><link href="https://putz.space/blog/intro-to-mastodon/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-09T18:51:36-05:00</published><updated>2019-09-09T18:51:36-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-09-09:/blog/intro-to-mastodon/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I decided to create a quick start guide for people to reference that's visually focused. I didn't find any guides that I particularly liked for onboarding a complete beginner, so I made my own. Feel free to share this as you please!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="faq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;F.A.Q: How does it work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
The following is meant as a quick guide. Focused on a heavy use of visuals. Should take no more than 10 minutes to read. Useful as a reference too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Targeted at &lt;a href="http://social.putz.space/" target="_blank"&gt;my own instance&lt;/a&gt;, but should be applicable to anyone's roughly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FYI:&lt;/strong&gt; you can log into any Mastodon server with an app. Check out &lt;a href="http://joinmastodon.org/apps"&gt;this list for one that suits you&lt;/a&gt;. Apps can add features that Mastodon itself is lacking while making the experience more cohesive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share how you will! Any questions not answered by this post can probably be found on &lt;a href="https://docs.joinmastodon.org/" target="_blank"&gt;https://docs.joinmastodon.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S: This document has been revised since it was created on the date above. Added links to apps, new sections covering more and fixed errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you feel comfortable with the technical details, then &lt;a href="https://putz.space/blog/making-friends-mastodon/"&gt;read here&lt;/a&gt; on how to make friends!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div id="toc"&gt;
&lt;p id="toc-header"&gt;Contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#faq"&gt;F.A.Q: How does it work?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#terminology"&gt;Terminology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#timelines"&gt;Timelines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#timeline-personal"&gt;Personal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#timeline-local"&gt;Local&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#timeline-federated"&gt;Federated&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#timeline-notifications"&gt;Notifications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#searching"&gt;Searching&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#searching-hashtag"&gt;Hashtags&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#searching-users"&gt;Users&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#profile"&gt;Profile preferences&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#public-profile"&gt;Public profile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#filtering-feeds"&gt;Filtering&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#filtering-posts"&gt;Post Filters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#filtering-users"&gt;Users&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#filtering-lists"&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#following"&gt;Following feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#posting"&gt;Posting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#post-privacy"&gt;Privacy settings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#content-warnings"&gt;Content Warnings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#post-poll"&gt;Polls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#account-migration"&gt;Account Migration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#comments"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="terminology"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Terminology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Mastodon specific words that you may encounter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Toot:&lt;/strong&gt; post (if birds &lt;em&gt;tweet&lt;/em&gt; then mastodons &lt;em&gt;toot&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boost, retoot:&lt;/strong&gt; a shared post or the act of sharing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instance:&lt;/strong&gt; a Mastodon server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite:&lt;/strong&gt; a like that notifies the poster and saves to a list of favorites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content Warning, cw:&lt;/strong&gt; a content warning lets you know what's coming before you read it. Can be a way to prepare people for sensitive conversations or long-winded ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Federation:&lt;/strong&gt; how posts reach your account since there's no singular central server. It's like a big game of telephone to get posts to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fedi, The Fediverse:&lt;/strong&gt; The web of applications that federate. i.e: &lt;a href="http://joinmastodon.org" target="_blank"&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://pixelfed.org" target="_blank"&gt;Pixelfed&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://pleroma.social/" target="_blank"&gt;Pleroma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://fediverse.party" target="_blank"&gt;etc&lt;/a&gt; are all social media platforms that share posts and users with one another.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="timelines"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Timelines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
There are types of feeds: &lt;strong&gt;Personal, Local&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Federated&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="timeline-personal"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Personal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
The &lt;strong&gt;Personal&lt;/strong&gt; timeline shows you the posts &amp;amp; boosts from people you follow. When you first join you'll only see posts from the administrator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you make friends and follow people, this will fill up (hopefully).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://putz.space/images/mastodon/followers-feed.png" alt="Personal feed" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="timeline-local"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Local&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
The &lt;strong&gt;Local&lt;/strong&gt; timeline is the place where everyone who is on the same server can talk to each other, like a town plaza. Here's a picture of how mine looks now. Depending on how many people are active this is usually a slower moving feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="local timeline" src="https://putz.space/images/mastodon/local-feed.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="timeline-federated"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Federated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
The &lt;strong&gt;Federated&lt;/strong&gt; timeline is a feed of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;everyone who is posting public messages on the &lt;strong&gt;Local&lt;/strong&gt; timeline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;people who who are followed by any user on the server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;boosted posts of the people those users follow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If connected to a relay, everyone on the fediverse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my case, we're connected to a relay with certain instances being blacklisted from mine for different reasons. However a relay is not necessary, in which case the community will probably be smaller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="federated timeline" src="https://putz.space/images/mastodon/federated-feed.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="timeline-notifications"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Notifications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notifications are given in a timeline as well. They update you with any mentions, follows, boosts of posts, favorites. You can use the configuration button to the right of the Notifications heading to filter what is shown too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="notification timeline" src="https://putz.space/images/mastodon/notifications-feed.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="searching"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Searching&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Finding stuff on Mastodon is fairly easy. The feeds automatically refresh if you scroll to the top. Hashtags are clickable to search for more posts. The search bar also lets you find things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can search for users, hashtags and on some servers even  post contents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://putz.space/images/mastodon/search-bar.png" alt="search bar" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="searching-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hashtag&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Let's look at the hashtags for example. All posts with &lt;strong&gt;#music&lt;/strong&gt; will be displayed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://putz.space/images/mastodon/search-hashtag.png" alt="hashtag search" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="searching-users"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Users&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users are searchable as well. You can either use just the username or the username and the domain name if you know it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://putz.space/images/mastodon/search-users.png" alt="hashtag search" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="profile"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Profile preferences&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To access click the preferences tab either at the end of navigation bar or the arrows next to your username.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://putz.space/images/mastodon/preferences.png" alt="preferences" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="public-profile"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Public profile&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Here you can edit your &lt;strong&gt;avatar&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;profile page image header&lt;/strong&gt;, set a &lt;strong&gt;description&lt;/strong&gt; and change your &lt;strong&gt;display name&lt;/strong&gt; as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can choose to make your account private so that only approved people can follow you. &lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt; This defaults your posts to private, so you'll have to manually set them to public to be visible on the local and federated timelines. By default it's the opposite if you're not set as private. More on that &lt;a href="#post-privacy"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://putz.space/images/mastodon/preferences-profile.png" alt="profile preferences" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The profile also includes a table that you can use to set labels and contents for things like indicating which website people can find your music at or even labeling your gender pronouns. It's customizable based on your own interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://putz.space/images/mastodon/profile-table.png" alt="profile preferences" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="filtering-feeds"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Filtering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Mastodon is about putting control of the feed back into not only community hands, but also into &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="filtering-posts"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Post Filters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
One option for this is in the preferences menu under filters. Here you can set posts with keywords to be automatically filtered and from whichever timeline for however long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://putz.space/images/mastodon/preferences-filters.png" alt="filters" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="filtering-users"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Users&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
On the timeline if you find someone annoying, just block them, mute them, or even report them. Especially if anyone from the federated timeline is harassing other users. To filter posts directly, click the elipses in the post to either report, block or silence a user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://putz.space/images/mastodon/post-menu.png" alt="filtering content" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="filtering-lists"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lists&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
To specifically follow different sets of users you can use lists. To access your lists use the menu at the end of the navigation bar or just navigate to &lt;strong&gt;Lists&lt;/strong&gt; if already visible. Useful for following a certain group of friends, people who post about a particular topic or whatever's important to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type in the textbox to create a new list. Click on the list then click on edit list in the configuration dropdown box pictured below to add or remove people you want to follow. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt; you must be following them to add them. The list only populates after creation too (old posts won't show up).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://putz.space/images/mastodon/lists.png" alt="lists" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="following"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Following feeds&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
In order to follow users click on their name and it will take you to their page. You'll see their landing page and toots. From here you can click follow in the upper right corner if you want to follow them or you can click the 3 dots to choose a different action. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what the public sees when they click on your page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://putz.space/images/mastodon/profile-page.png" alt="profile page" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="posting"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Posting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
To post click the compose button in the bottom right corner or the reply arrow on a toot. If you're on desktop it could be visible on the left-hand side already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="post-privacy"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Privacy settings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Mastodon allows you to set 4 different privacy settings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public:&lt;/strong&gt; everyone can see it (federated)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unlisted:&lt;/strong&gt; everyone can see it, but it's not on the public timelines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Private:&lt;/strong&gt; only followers can see (not the public)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Direct message:&lt;/strong&gt; only addressed users get the message&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://putz.space/images/mastodon/post-privacy.png" alt="post privacy settings" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="content-warnings"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Content Warnings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you click on CW it will label the post behind a content warning that will hide your post until it's clicked. This is useful for sensitive subjects or really long posts so that they don't clog up the feed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Popular content warnings include but are not limited to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NSFW or lewd&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pol (politics)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;selfie (eye contenat/no eye contact)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;long&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;meta (regarding mastodon)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;abuse (thoughts or stories relating to abuse)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mh (mental health)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://putz.space/images/mastodon/post-content-warning.png" alt="posting comments" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="post-poll"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Polls&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
You can start a poll that will notify users of results after expiration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://putz.space/images/mastodon/post-poll.png" alt="poll" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="account-migration"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Account Migration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Given the federated nature of the platform, you may decide to change servers some day but still want to keep the list of people you're following, people you've blocked and more. Not everything can be exported, but it can make transitioning to a new account much smoother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also choose to delete your account as well, but that's permanent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://putz.space/images/mastodon/profile-import-export.png" alt="poll" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="comments"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Comments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://social.putz.space/@pootz/102720566051051746/embed" class="mastodon-embed" style="max-width: 100%; border: 0" width="100%" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;script src="https://social.putz.space/embed.js" async="async"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="blog"></category><category term="tech"></category><category term="social"></category><category term="mastodon"></category></entry><entry><title>An invitation to social.putz.space</title><link href="https://putz.space/blog/social/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-01T14:53:39-05:00</published><updated>2019-09-01T14:53:39-05:00</updated><author><name>putz</name></author><id>tag:putz.space,2019-09-01:/blog/social/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I finally decided to set up a mastodon server to host social media for me and my friends! This is an invitation to folks to join. I've sent it to people directly as a way to ask if they're interested, but if you happen to stumble across this on accident feel free to read it over. Register if it makes you interested!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://cf.mastohost.com/v1/AUTH_91eb37814936490c95da7b85993cc2ff/socialputzspace/site_uploads/files/000/000/002/original/portada-new.png" alt="front page for social.putz.space" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The new social media&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven't heard yet, I've joined a new social media platform called Mastodon. It's one of many platforms on &lt;a href="https://fediverse.party/en/fediverse/" target="_blank"&gt;"The Fediverse"&lt;/a&gt;, where a bunch of different social media platforms co-exist. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long story short, I'm inviting people to join me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don't feel like reading, here's the link: &lt;a href="http://social.putz.space"&gt;social.putz.space&lt;/a&gt;. If you want to know more before checking it out, then see below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div id="toc"&gt;
&lt;p id="toc-header"&gt;Contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#why-join"&gt;Why Join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#community-building"&gt;Building a community&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#join"&gt;How do I join social.putz.space?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#faq"&gt;F.A.Q: How does it work?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="why-join"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why join?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Social media these days is creepy, and at worst downright harmful. Platforms like Facebook &amp;amp; Instagram spy on you to sell you products, ideas and even just memes. They jumble it all together on a mysterious feed that you don't control then it selectively shows content from friends at random (often just sharing the same ads) to keep you coming back so it actually has any meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, it's hard to actually connect with people. It's like being in a bar so noisy that you can barely think over the ads to buy beer blaring over the speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fediverse is seeking to change that. It allows you to build an online community that's better connected. It allows that community to run things how it wants while still being connected to other servers and platforms doing the exact same thing so it's still global.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm inviting you to come build that community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="community-building"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Building a community&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
I use the word &lt;em&gt;build&lt;/em&gt; on purpose, because it's going to take some effort to make this happen. If I just shared this without reaching out directly, you'd probably miss it or scroll passed. Facebook has gone to great lengths to build a particular kind of community, one that collectively consumes information for sale. It's not an accident that it operates the way it does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To build an alternative also means doing it on purpose then, but it's worth the effort. On one hand, I want to connect with friends and see how y'all are doing without it getting lost in Facebook's manipulative bullshit. You don't have to be political, think a certain way or have any goals in mind. This is not a hivemind. You can share memes, jokes, posts about your day or whatever game/movie you're checking out right now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use this space how you like! That's an important part of what I mean by building and fostering a community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as importantly though, I see this as a way to stay connected to people I know who care about the world. Because of resource limitations, and also to maintain a cohesive community, I've reached out selectively to some close friends that I think would be interested in this project to start. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should feel free to invite others too! I trust your judgement. I think you're all really cool people that are worth staying in touch with. If it gets too big though we might have to talk about upgrading resources or bring on people to help moderate lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I'm trying to say though is that in order to deal with the bullshit that the world is going through right now, it's also good to have this space to talk to one another without all the distractions and censorship. Not only is community important, but so is how it's built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don't even have to leave Facebook either if you don't want to. That's the beauty of this, it's not exclusive. It's just a quieter place where you can  still be social without wading through a toxic swamp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="join"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How do I join social.putz.space?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Ready to dive in? It's simple! Just sign up for an account at &lt;a href="http://social.putz.space" target="_blank"&gt;social.putz.space&lt;/a&gt;. Choose your name then let me know either why you're joining or just who you are if I know you. Once registered, I'll approve your account when I get the email notification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I have limited space I'm sticking to either approving friends or friends of friends. As we grow, things may start to get slower, in which case I'll have to upgrade my hosting plan. Don't let that stop you from joining though, I'm just putting out a warning in case you see sign-ups are closed at some point or any technical difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're joining, then take some time to read the information below to get familiar with the platform! Others have written at length too about Mastodon, so you can google something if it's not here. There are apps for every device you can think of too, so if you don't like using a web browser &lt;a href="https://joinmastodon.org/apps" target="_blank"&gt;check out the apps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="faq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;F.A.Q: How does it work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
There are technically other servers where you can sign up, but I've opened up my own server with the purpose of connecting people I know. Think of it as being in my living room or out on the porch chillin'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to get a better understanding of how to use the actual platform itself, I recommend reading &lt;a href="https://putz.space/blog/intro-to-mastodon/"&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt; that I've made since initially sending out this invitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="blog"></category><category term="tech"></category><category term="social"></category></entry></feed>